<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Angels and Saints</string>
    <string name="creed">I believe in God, the Father Almighty, Creator of Heaven and earth; and
        in Jesus Christ, His only Son, Our Lord, Who was conceived by the Holy Spirit, born of the Virgin Mary, suffered
        under Pontius Pilate, was crucified; died, and was buried. He descended into Hell; the third day He arose again
        from the dead; He ascended into Heaven, sitteth at the right hand of God, the Father Almighty; from thence He
        shall come to judge the living and the dead. I believe in the Holy Spirit, the holy Catholic Church, the
        communion of saints, the forgiveness of sins, the resurrection of the body, and the life everlasting. \n\nAmen.
        \n\n\n

    </string>
    <string name="apostles">Apostles\' Creed</string>
    <string name="god_the_father">Lords Prayer</string>
    <string name="our_father">Our Father who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come.
        Thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven. \n\nGive us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our
        trespasses,
        as we forgive those who trespass against us, and lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.

        For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever and ever.
        \n\n
        Amen.\n\n\n


    </string>
    <string name="our_father_mar">
        आमच्या स्वर्गीयबापा\n\n

        आमच्या स्वर्गीय बापा, तुझे नाव पवित्र मानले जावो, तुझे राज्य येवो. जसे स्वर्गात तसे पृथ्वीवरही तुझ्या
        इच्छेप्रमाणे होवो. \n\nआमची दररोजची भाकर आज आम्हाला दे. जशी आम्ही आमचा अपराध करणाऱ्यांना क्षमा करतो तशी तू
        आमच्या अपराधांची क्षमा कर आणि आम्हाला मोहात पडू देऊ नकोस पण वाईटापासून आम्हाला सोडव. \n\nआमेन.
    </string>
    <string name="hail_mary">Hail Mary</string>
    <string name="hailmary">Hail Mary, full of grace. Our Lord is with you. Blessed are you among women,
        and blessed is the fruit of your womb, Jesus.\n \nHoly Mary, Mother of God pray for us sinners, now and at the
        hour of our death. \n \nAmen


    </string>
    <string name="hail_mar">
        नमो कृपापूर्ण मरिये, प्रभू तुझ्या ठायी आहे. धन्य तू स्त्रियांमध्ये धन्य तुझ्या उदराचे फळ येशू.\n\n
        हे पवित्र मरिये, देवाचे माते, आम्हा पाप्यांसाठी आता आणि आमच्या मरणाच्या वेळी विनंती कर, \n\nआमेन.
    </string>
    <string name="holy_queen">Hail holy queen</string>
    <string name="hail_queen">Hail, holy Queen, Mother of Mercy! Our life, our sweetness, and our hope! To thee do we
        cry, poor banished children of Eve, to thee do we send up our sighs, mourning and weeping in this valley, of
        tears. Turn, then, most gracious advocate, thine eyes of mercy toward us; and after this our exile show unto us
        the blessed fruit of thy womb Jesus; O clement, O loving, O sweet virgin Mary. Pray for us, O holy Mother of God
        That we may be made worthy of the promises of Christ.
        \n\n\n

    </string>
    <string name="holy_mar">
        नमस्कार हे राणी\n\n

        नमस्कार हे राणी, दयेचे माते ! तू आमचे जीवन, आमचे माधुर्य आणि आमची आशा, तुला नमस्कार असो. तुझ्याकडे आम्ही देशपार
        झालेली एवेची मुले मोठ्याने आक्रोश करतो. तुझ्याकडे आम्ही या अश्रूंच्या दरीत शोक करत व रडत सुस्कारे टाकतो. तूच तर
        आमची कैवारीण आहेस, म्हणून तू आपली दयेची दृष्टी आम्हाकडे लाव आणि आमच्या या देशपारीनंतर तुझ्या उदराचे आशीर्वादित
        फळ येशू याचे आम्हाला दर्शन घडव. हे कृपाळू, हे ममताळू, हे मधुर कुमारी मरिया.\n\n
        - ख्रिस्ताने दिलेल्या वचनास आम्ही पात्र व्हावे म्हणून हे पवित्र देवमाते, आम्हासाठी विनंती कर.
    </string>
    <string name="fatima_prayer">Fatima Prayer</string>
    <string name="jesus">Oh my Jesus, forgive us of our sins. Save us from the fires of hell. Lead all
        souls into heaven, especially those in most need of thy mercy.\n


    </string>
    <string name="fatima_mar">
        हे येशू, आमच्या पापांची क्षमा कर. पापदंडापासून आमचे रक्षण कर. सर्व मनुष्यांना आणि विशेषकरून ज्यांना तुझ्या
        दयेची अधिक गरज आहे त्यांना स्वर्गाकडे ने. \n\nआमेन.
    </string>
    <string name="holy_communion">Prayers after Holy Communion</string>
    <string name="blood">What has passed our lips as food, O Lord, may we possess
        in purity of heart, that what is given to us in time, be our healing for eternity. May Your Body, O Lord, which
        I have eaten, and Your Blood which I have drunk, cleave to my very soul, and grant that no trace of sin be found
        in me, whom these pure and holy mysteries have renewed. Who live and reign, world without end. Amen. We humbly
        beseech You, almighty god, to grant that those whom You refresh with Your sacraments, may serve you worthily by
        a life well pleasing to You. Through our Lord Jesus Christ, Your Son, Who lives and reigns, world without end.
        Amen.
    </string>
    <string name="_creed">Apostles Creed</string>
    <string name="lords">lords prayer</string>
    <string name="hail">Hail Mary</string>
    <string name="queen">Hail Holy Queen</string>
    <string name="communion">Prayer after holy communion</string>
    <string name="simon">\nPeter, who was also known as Simon Peter of Cephas, is considered the first Pope. Despite his
        papacy, Peter had humble beginnings and became one of the Twelve Apostles of Jesus. He was ordained by Jesus as
        the \"Rock of My Church\" written in Matthew 16:18, which says, \"And I tell you that you are Peter,and on this
        rock I will build my church, and the gates of Hades will not overcome it.\"
        \n\n
        Peter was a native of Bethsaida, near Lake Tiberias and was the son of Jonah. He and his brother Andrew were
        fishermen on Lake Genesareth. Peter followed Jesus and his life was changed forever. Though he was one of the
        first disciples called to follow Jesus and eventually became the spokesman for the group, Peter is known for his
        \"little faith.\"
        \n\n
        Peter is often depicted in the gospels as spokesman of all the Apostles.
        In the time following Christ\'s Ascension, Peter stood as the unquestionable head of the Apostles, which the
        book of Acts clearly describes. He went on to appoint the replacement of Judas Iscariot, spoke first to the
        crowds that had assembled after the descent of the Holy Spirit at Pentecost, he was the first Apostle to perform
        miracles in the name of the Lord, and he rendered judgment upon the deceitful Ananias and Sapphira, both of whom
        were stealing from church members and God alike.
        Peter was instrumental in bringing the Gospel to the Gentiles. He baptized the Roman pagan Cornelius, and at the
        Council of Jerusalem gave his support to preach to Gentiles, thereby permitting the new Church to become
        universal.
        \n\n
        Tradition says that Peter died in A.D. 64-68 during Nero\'s persecution of the Christians. He was crucified
        upside down on a cross.
        \n\n
        Feastday June 29th.
    </string>
    <string name="andrew">\nSt. Andrew, also known as Andrew the Apostle, was an Apostle and the older brother
        to St. Peter.
        \n\n
        According to the New Testament, Andrew was born in the village of Bethsaida on the Sea of Galilee during the
        early first century. Much like his younger brother, Simon Peter, Andrew was also a fisherman. Andrew\"s very
        name means strong and he was known for having good social skills.
        \n\n
        In the Gospel of Matthew, it is said Jesus was walking along the shore of the Sea of Galilee and saw Andrew and
        Simon Peter fishing. It is then he asked the two to become disciples and \"fishers of men.\"
        \n\n
        In the Gospel of Luke, Andrew is not initially named. It describes Jesus using a boat, believed to be solely
        Simon\"s, to preach to the multitudes and catch a large amount of fish on a night that originally was dry.
        Later, in Luke 5:7, it mentions Simon was not the only fisherman on the boat, but it is not until Luke 6:14 that
        there is talk of Andrew being Simon Peter\"s brother.
        \n\n
        However, the Gospel of John tells a separate story, stating Andrew was a disciple of John the Baptist. When
        Jesus walked by one day, John the Baptist stated, \"Behold, the Lamb of God!\" It is then that Andrew and
        another made the decision to follow Jesus.
        \n\n
        Little else is said about Andrew in the Gospels, but it is believed Andrew was one of the closer disciples to
        Jesus. It was he who told Jesus about the boy with the loaves and fishes, according to John 6:8. When Philip
        wanted to speak to Jesus about Greeks seeking him, he spoke to Andrew first. Andrew was also present at the last
        supper.
        \n\n
        Per Christian tradition, Andrew went on to preach the Good News around the shores of the Black Sea and
        throughout what is now Greece and Turkey. Andrew was martyred by crucifixion in Patras. He was bound, rather
        than nailed, to a cross, as is described in the Acts of Andrew. He was crucified on a cross form known as \"crux
        decussata,\" which is an X-shaped cross or a \"saltire.\" Today this is commonly referred to as \"St. Andrew\"s
        Cross.\" It is believed Andrew requested to be crucified this way, because he deemed himself \"unworthy to be
        crucified on the same type of cross as Jesus.\"
        \n\n
        Andrew\"s remains were originally preserved at Patras. However, some believe St. Regulus, who was a monk at
        Patras, received a vision telling him to hide some of Andrew\"s bones. Shortly after Regulus\" dream, many of
        Andrew\"s relics were transferred to Constantinople by order of Roman emperor Constantius II around 357. Regulus
        later received orders in a second dream telling him to take the bones \"to the ends of the earth.\" He was to
        build a shrine for them wherever he shipwrecked. He landed on the coat of Fife, Scotland.
        \n\n
        St. Andrew is venerated in Georgia as the first preacher of Christianity in that territory and in Cyprus for
        having struck the rocks creating a gush of healing waters upon landing on the shore.
        \n\n
        His saltire cross is featured on the flag of Scotland and is represented in much of his iconography. He is
        commonly portrayed as an old man with long white hair and a beard, often holding the Gospel book or a scroll.
        \n\n
        St. Andrew is the patron saint of fishermen and singers. He is also the patron saint to several countries and
        cities including: Scotland, Romania, Russia, Ukraine and Patras.
        \n\n
        Feastday November 30.
    </string>
    <string name="james">James Major is the son of Zebedee and Salome and brother of John the disciple. The title \"the
        Greater\" was added to St.
        James\' name to help distinguish him from the Apostle James \"the Less,\" who is believed to have been shorter
        than James \"the Greater.\" Saint James the Greater was one of Jesus\' first disciples.
        \n\n
        James was fishing with his father and John the Apostle when Jesus came to the shores of the Sea of Galilee and
        called for the fisherman, who were unable to catch any fish that day, to dip their nets in the water once again.
        When the fishermen followed Jesus\' instructions, they found their nets full, and after emptying the fish on
        board, the boats nearly sank from their weight.
        \n\n
        Later, James was one of only three called by Jesus to witness his Transfiguration, and when he and his brother
        wanted to call fire upon a Samaritan town, both were rebuked by Jesus. Following Christ\'s Ascension, James
        spread the Gospel across Israel and the Roman kingdom as well. He traveled and spread the Word for nearly forty
        years in Spain. It is said that one day, as he prayed, The Blessed Virgin Mary appeared to him and asked him to
        build her a church, which he did.
        \n\n
        Later, James returned to Jerusalem but was martyred for his faith by King Herod, who decapitated him. Saint
        James the Greater is known as the first apostle to die. As he was not allowed to be buried following his
        martyrdom, his remains were taken to Compostela, Spain, by some of his followers, who buried him. In the ninth
        century his remains were discovered and moved to a tomb in Santiago de Compostela. Today, his remains can still
        be found in the Cathedral of Santiago. As Santiago de Compostela is the most frequently visited place pilgrims
        migrate to following Rome and Jerusalem, Pope Leo declared it a shrine.
        \n\n
        Feastday July 25th.
    </string>
    <string name="john_">\nSt. John the Apostle, the son of Zebedee and Salome, was one of the Twelve Apostles of Jesus.
        John was called to be an Apostle by our Lord in the first year of His public ministry. He is considered the same
        person as John the Evangelist, John of Patmos and the Beloved Disciple. John\'s older brother was St. James the
        Great, another one of Jesus\' Twelve Apostles. Jesus referred to the brothers as \"Boanerges,\" meaning \"sons
        of thunder.\" John is believed to be the longest living apostle and the only not to die a martyr\'s death.
        \n\n
        John, along with Peter and James, were the only witnesses of the raising of Daughter of Jairus, and the closest
        witnesses to the Agony in Gethsemane.
        \n\n
        John was the only one of the Twelve Apostles who did not forsake the Savior in the hour of His Passion. He stood
        faithfully at the cross when the Savior made him the guardian of His Mother.
        \n\n
        After the Assumption of Mary, John went to Ephesus, according to Church tradition. He later became banished by
        the Roman authorities to the Greek Island of Patmos; this is where he allegedly wrote the Book of Revelation. It
        is said John was banished in the late 1st century, during the reign of the Emperor Domitian, after being plunged
        into boiling oil in Rome and suffering no injuries. It is also said that all those who witnessed the miracle in
        the Colosseum were converted to Christianity. Emperor Domitian was known for his persecution of Christians.
        \n\n
        John is known as the author of the Gospel of John and four other books in the New Testament - the three Epistles
        of John and the Book of Revelation. The authorship of the Gospel is credited to the \"disciple whom Jesus
        loved,\" and John 21:24 claims the Gospel of John is based on the \"Beloved Disciple\'s\" testimony.
        \n\n
        St. John is called the Apostle of Charity, a virtue he had learned from his Divine Master, and which he
        constantly inculcated by word and example. The \"beloved disciple\" died in Ephesus after AD 98, where a stately
        church was erected over his tomb.
        \n\n
        St. John is the patron saint of love, loyalty, friendships, and authors. He is often depicted in art as the
        author of the Gospel with an eagle, symbolizing \"the height he rose to in his gospel.\" In other icons, he is
        shown looking up into heaven and dictating his Gospel to his disciple.
        \n\n
        Feastday December 27
    </string>
    <string name="old">Old testament(46 Books)\n\n</string>
    <string name="testament">New testament(27 Books)\n\n</string>
    <string name="apostles_1">Apostles</string>
    <string name="common_prayer">Common Prayers</string>
    <string name="angels_">Angels</string>
    <string name="pray">Pray to the guardian angel</string>
    <string name="angel">Prayer To The Guardian Angel</string>
    <string name="angel_of_god">Angel of God , guardian of my soul , mind and body watch over me. Protect me from all
        dangers and attacks of Satan. Lead me to the right path of perfection. Intercede for me always before the throne
        of God. Do not leave me alone , not even a moment. Hold my hands , that I may reach heaven safely. Jesus my
        Savior and God wash me and my dear ones and all I have in your precious blood. Protect us and fill us with your
        eternal love. Thank you Jesus !! Praise you Jesus !!
    </string>
    <string name="highest">\n\nThey are the highest and closest angels to God.
        The name \"Seraphim\" comes from the Hebrew word Saraf which means to \"burn\" or \"destroy\" and it refers to
        the ability of the seraphim to destroy by burning. They are burning with love of God and with that flame it
        burns the sins of human beings and the power of evil spirit.

        In the book of Isaiah 6:6-7 one Seraphim takes a burning coal and touches it to Isaiah\'s lips,
        proclaiming that his guilt is taken away and his sin is forgiven.
        Having burned with love of God they spread this love to us. Seraph means \'love\'.
        In Hebrew it also means \"one who is blazing\", Seraphims are the created representations of divine love,
        the fire of which consumes them and keeps them close to the throne of God.
        They are the only angels to stand above the throne. They establish the vibration of love which in turn creates
        the
        field of life. They purify completely and dispel the shadows of darkness. They are of such subtlety that they
        are rarely
        perceived by human consciousness. \n\nThe seraphims sing the hourly \"holy, holy, holy\" and also give us the
        grace to praise God.
        Seraphims help humans perfect the flame of love. The seraphims have six fiery red wings and bare a flaming
        sword; their feet are bare. Seraphims help humans perfect the flame of love. Seraf means \'Love\'. In Hebrew it
        also means \"one who is flaming\".
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nTo give the grace of Praise, and share genuine love.

    </string>
    <string name="cherubim_rank">\nCherubims are the second highest angels to God. The Hebrew term \"kerub\" means
        \"fullness of knowledge and wisdom\" The cherubims are not specifically called angels. They make their first
        appearance in the Bible in Genesis 3:22. God places them at the east entrance to the Garden of Eden, guarding it
        with flaming swords.

        In Exodus 25:10-22, God gives Moses instructions for building the Ark of the Covenant, a gilded wooden chest
        that shall bear the mercy seat of God with cherubim made of hammered gold at its two ends.

        \n\nThey bestow on us wisdom and knowledge. Cherubims have two blue wings and shod feet, and they may hold open
        books representing the fullness of knowledge. They may stand on wheels. The cherubims contemplate the divine
        goodness not directly and in itself but as providence. They are the fullness of science because they see clearly
        the first operative virtue of the divine model of things.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nThey are the Holy Ones, who lead to holiness through the practice of virtues.
    </string>
    <string name="thrones_are">\nThrones of the third rank contemplate the enactment of divine justice. They are called
        Thrones, for the power of judgment is shown by the throne. They are the bearers of God and fully capable of
        undertaking all that is divine. They incessantly praise God, and help us to listen to the voice of God and give
        us the virtue of humility.

        Thrones are two fiery wheels with four eye-filled wings each; they may carry sceptre, orbs, swords, or books.
        They may carry thrones or seat representing divine justice.
        \n\n <b>Mission</b>\n\nThey give the grace to listen to God and of genuine humility.
    </string>
    <string name="dominions_are">\nDominions are the fourth highest order of angels, who regulate the duties of other
        angels and make known the commands of God. Dominions also are Channels of mercy. The term dominion refers to
        \"lordship,\" \"rule,\" or \"special meaning.\" Ephesians 1:21 states that God has raised Christ far above \"all
        rule and authority and power and dominion and every name that is named.\" And Colossians 1:16 states that in
        Jesus Christ all things visible and invisible, in heaven and earth are created, \"whether thrones or dominions
        or rulers powers.\"

        Dominions are two-winged, wear long albs, golden girdles, and green stoles, hold the seal of Jesus Christ in
        their right hands and a golden staff topped by a cross in their left hands. They also have crowns and they carry
        scepters, orbs, swords, or books.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nThey reflect the authority of God. They control the senses and remove evil tendencies.
        They save us from the deception and temptation of the devil.
    </string>
    <string name="virtues_are">\nThe fifth highest order of angels, whose name means \"Virtues,\" especially in
        relation to performance of miracles and magic. The primary tasks of Virtues are to execute miracles on earth and
        provide courage, grace and valour. They help carry out the suggestions of Authorities. They control the natural
        powers and help to balance the equillibrium and seasons. They help to enlighten the intelligence and give us
        wisdom and knowledge. They give us strength and courage to fight against evils. They are also known as the
        heavenly powers, meaning that the celestial powers will be shaken (Luke 21:26). The general directives issued by
        Dominations are received by Virtues, who multiply them and channel them according to the various effects to be
        produced.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nThey are the Souls of the prophets. They reveal the Principles of God.
    </string>
    <string name="powers">\nThe sixth highest order of angels, Powers fight against evil spirits who seek to wreck
        havoc through human beings. They protect the divine plans initiated by the Dominions and carried out by the
        virtues. They are sometimes equated with authorities, Dynameis, and Exousial. They help us to obey the
        commandments of God. They protect the earth from the Satanic destructions. St. Paul alluded to their capability
        to be either good or evil: Romans 8:38, he lists Powers as among obstacles that will not be able to separate man
        from the love of God in Jesus Christ. Pope Gregory the great said powers presided over Demons. Like Dominions
        and Virtues, Powers are two winged, wear long albs, golden girdles, and green stoles, hold the seal of Jesus
        Christ in their right hands. Powers sometimes hold rods or swords, wear knightly armor, and lead demons in
        chains. 1 Pet. 3:22 says that Jesus Christ went to heaven and is seated at the right hand side of God. Angels
        and Authorities and Powers are made subject to Him.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nThey give us the strength to carry out God\' commandments and save us from falling into
        temptation.
    </string>
    <string name="archangels">\nArchangels are the Eighth highest rank of angels. The name \"archangels\" comes from
        the Greek term \"archangelos.\" meaning \"chief messenger\" or \"eminent messenger.\" Archangels, also known as
        \"Holy Ones.\" are the communicators between God and human beings. They are incharge of Heaven\'s armies in the
        battle against Hell, and they are the supervisor\'s of the Guardian Angels. They also act as guardian angels of
        leaders of religions and states. Archangels have a special place before God. In the Book of Revelation we can
        see \"seven angels who stand before God\" Rev 8:2, there are seven punishing angels in the book of Ezekiel six,
        who wield swords and a seventh who carries a writing case (Eze 9:2); Raphael revealed himself to Tobit as one of
        the seven angels who stand in the presence of the Lord (Tobit 12:15). Archangels are seen as soldiers in armour
        with two wings, golden belts, and javelins. They are Michael, Gabriel, Raphel. Uriel, Jeramiel, Raguel and
        Saraqael.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nThey act against evil spirits and confirm us in faith and good work.
    </string>
    <string name="angels__">\nAngels are attached to a person from birth to death. providing constant guidance,
        protection, and companionship. Raphael, the guardian angel of all humanity, is represented as a benign friend
        and fellow traveller, protector of the young and innocent, rendered in episodes from the book of Tobit.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>They are the Heavenly armies, all the angels protect the children of God. They also give us
        protection during our life and accompany us to heaven.
    </string>
    <string name="philip">\nSt.Philip was born in Bethsaida, Galilee. He may have been a disciple of John the Baptist
        and is
        mentioned as one of the Apostles in the lists of Matthew, Mark, Luke, and in Acts. He was called by Jesus
        Himself and brought Nathanael to Christ. Philip was present at the miracle of the loaves and fishes, when he
        engaged in a brief dialogue with the Lord, and was the Apostle approached by the Hellenistic Jews from Bethsaida
        to introduce them to Jesus. Just before the Passion, Jesus answered Philip\'s query to show them the Father, but
        no further mention of Philip is made in the New Testament beyond his listing among the Apostles awaiting the
        Holy Spirit in the Upper Room.
        \n\n
        Following the resurrection of Jesus, Philip was sent with his sister Mariamne and Bartholomew to preach in
        Greece, Phrygia, and Syria.Of the four Gospels, Philip figures most prominently in the Gospel of John. Jesus is
        asked by Philip on how to feed the 5,000 people.Later he appears as a link to the Greek community. Philip bore a
        Greek name, may have spoken Greek,and may have been known to the Greek pilgrims in Jerusalem. He advises Andrew
        that certain Greeks wish to meet Jesus, and together they inform Jesus of this (John 12:21).During the Last
        Supper, when Philip asked Jesus to show them the Father, he provides Jesus the opportunity to teach his
        disciples about the unity of the Father and the Son.
        \n\n
        Death of St.Philip
        \n\n
        Philip was martyred in the city of Hierapolis, where through a miraculous healing and his preaching Philip
        converted the wife of the proconsul of the city. This
        enraged the proconsul, and he had Philip, Bartholomew, and Mariamne all tortured. Philip and Bartholomew were
        then crucified upside-down, and Philip preached from his cross. As a result of Philip\'s preaching the crowd
        released Bartholomew from his cross, but Philip insisted that they not release him, and Philip died on the
        cross.Nowadays relics of Philip the Apostle are in the crypt of Basilica Santi Apostoli, Rome.
        \n\n
        Saint Philip is the patron saint of hatters.
        \n\n
        Feastday May 3
    </string>
    <string name="bartholomew">\nAll that is known of him with certainty is that he is mentioned in the synoptic gospels
        and Acts as one of the twelve apostles. His name, a patronymic, means \"son of Tolomai\" and scholars believe he
        is the same as Nathanael mentioned in John, who says he is from Cana and that Jesus called him an
        \"Israelite…incapable of deceit.\" The Roman Martyrology says he preached in India and Greater Armenia, where he
        was flayed and beheaded by King Astyages. Tradition has the place as Abanopolis on the west coast of the Caspian
        Sea and that he also preached in Mesopotamia, Persia, and Egypt. The Gospel of Bartholomew is apochryphal and
        was condemned in the decree of Pseudo-Gelasius.
        \n\n
        Feast Day August 24.
    </string>
    <string name="guardian">\nThe concept of guardian spirits is ancient and universal: guardian angels are particularly
        prominent in Catholicism. Guardian angels are not expressly named so in the Bible, but the concept of personal
        angels is established in various passages. In Ez. 28:14, God says \"An anointed Cherub is appointed to guard
        you\". From the time of our birth God appoints specially anointed angels to protect us so that the evil spirit
        and his activities may not take possession of us. In Baruch 6:7 it is written: \"My Angel is with you. He is
        guarding your life.\"
        \n\n
        Guardian angels are from the 9th order. God the Father lets us know His will through these spirits, burning with
        love of God. He has appointed them as our guardians and guides. (Ps. 91:11-12). They always walk with us as
        fellow travellers and take care of us, protect us in danger, divert us from evil endeavours, strengthen us. when
        we face sorrows and misery. The angel offers before God our necessities and our Sorrows. The gospel of St.
        Mathew 18:10-11 says \"you must not insult even the least of these, because their angels are always seeing the
        face of God. The intercession of the guardian angels is very powerful. They advise men to be righteous. (Job.
        33:23-24)
        \n\n
        There are separate Guardian Angels for each country and city. (Dan 10:13-21). We must respect them and pray for
        their aid Our guardian angels can make communications with the saints in heaven. They constantly intercede for
        us. When you begin to travel securely along the spiritual path they pray to Heaven for giving you most valuable
        graces. When there is a threat to your spiritual growth, your guardian angel warns you before hand. They do this
        in various ways. The voice of our guardian angels is experienced by means of whispers and voice from within Our
        guardian angels can help us even from falling into dangers. A spiritual enlightenment of the human soul is the
        sole aim of the creation of angels. We will be led by the angels invoking the grace of God, for ever.
        \n\n
        Genesis 32:1 tells that \"Jacob went on his way and the angels of God met him.\" implying that he had personal
        angels protecting him on his journey. In Psalm 91:11-13. God \"will give his angels charge of you to guard you
        in all your ways. On their hands they will bear you up .lest you dash your foot against a stone. Angels are two
        winged and may appear as soldiers, or they may wear ecclesiastical garments They frequently wear a diadem with a
        cross in the front. A late medieval variation was to show them in clothing made of feathers. They carry many
        objects: candles, musical instruments, scrolls, and inscribed shields.
        \n

    </string>
    <string name="guardian_2">
        <b>How does the Guardian Angel help us?</b>
        \n\n
        The primary purpose of the guardian angel is the salvation of the soul It serves as messenger, bringing God\'s
        inspiration and gudince, and as protector against harm and evil. The guardian angel has also been called the
        angel of prayer, angel of peace. and angel of repentance 1Timo,24 notes that God desires all men to be saved and
        to come to the knowledge of the truth. The Catholic church teaches that guardian angels watch over humanity as a
        shepherd over his flock. Angels are joyful and happy to promote the welfare of human souls, for it is the will
        of God
        \n\n
        There are several ways that guardian angels help people. according to Catechism
        \n\n
        1. They put good thoughts into minds, and move the will to do what is good
        \n\n
        2. They pray with the people and for the people, and offer their
        prayers and good works to God.
        \n\n
        3. They reveal the will of God.
        \n\n
        4. They receive and protect the soul at the moment of death. The guardian angel guides it to the after world,
        protecting it from the onslaught of demons who attempt to steal it away to hell
        \n\n
        5. Guardian angels praise God. Angels continuously sing the glory of God, and they encourage humans to do the
        same.
        \n\n
        6. Guardian angels of nations are referred to as Princes (Daniel 10:13)
        \n\n
        7. Protects us from danger
        \n\n
        8. Guards us from falling into sin
        \n\n
        9. When we have a tendency to commit sin, he obstructs it
        \n\n
        10. Warns us about the consequences of sin
        \n\n
        11. Helps us to rethink and leads us to a life of reparation
        \n\n
        12. Gives us the strength and inspiration to acknowledge our faults.
        \n\n
        13. Induces us to give up revengeful actions and revengeful thoughts.
        \n\n
        14. Guards us under his wings.
        \n\n
        15.Spreads wings in front of us so that we may not see unbecoming sights.
        \n\n
        16. Gives strength and helps to keep our good resolutions
        \n\n
        17. The angel induces and helps us to restore friendship with those who are away from us through hatred.
        \n\n
        18. Helps those who are afraid to speak to an angry person. removes their anger and enables them to behave
        gently
        \n\n
        19. Reminds us of things we need.
        \n\n
        20. If we pray to them, who constantly see the face of God, they will help us to have a vision of God or
        experience the presence of God when we pray.
        \n\n
        21. The angel will help to find lost articles.
        \n\n
        22. It is enough to tell our Guardian Angel to remind others of certain things.
        \n\n
        23. Things pertaining to jobs will be done quickly if we tell the Guardian Angel of the Officers.

    </string>
    <string name="thomas">\nSt. Thomas was born a Jew and was called to be one of the twelve Apostles. His birth and
        death
        dates are unknown, but his feast day is celebrated July 3.
        \n\n
        He was a dedicated but impetuous follower of Christ. When Jesus said He was returning to Judea to visit His sick
        friend Lazarus, Thomas immediately exhorted the other Apostles to accompany Him on the trip which involved
        certain danger and possible death because of the mounting hostility of the authorities.
        \n\n
        At the Last Supper, when Christ told His disciples that He was going to prepare a place for them to which they
        also might come because they knew both the place and the way, Thomas pleaded that they did not understand and
        received the beautiful assurance that Christ is the Way, the Truth, and the Life.
        \n\n
        St. Thomas is best known for his role in verifying the Resurrection of his Master. Thomas\' unwillingness to
        believe that the other Apostles had seen their risen Lord on the first Easter Sunday earned him the title of
        \"doubting Thomas.\"
        \n\n
        Eight days later, on Christ\'s second apparition, Thomas was gently rebuked for his skepticism and furnished
        with the evidence he had demanded - seeing in Christ\'s hands the point of the nails. Thomas even put his
        fingers in the nail holes and his hand into Christ\'s side. After verifying the wounds were true, St. Thomas
        became convinced of the reality of the Resurrection and exclaimed, \"My Lord and My God,\" thus making a public
        Profession of Faith in the Divinity of Jesus.
        \n\n
        St. Thomas is also mentioned as being present at another Resurrection appearance of Jesus - at Lake Tiberias,
        when a miraculous catch of fish occurred.
        \n\n
        This is all that we know about St. Thomas from the New Testament. Tradition says that at the dispersal of the
        Apostles after Pentecost this saint was sent to evangelize to the Parthians, Medes, and Persians. He ultimately
        reached India, carrying the Faith to the Malabar coast, which still boasts a large native population calling
        themselves \"Christians of St. Thomas.\"
        \n\n
        According to tradition, Thomas was killed in an accident when a fowler shot at a peacock and struck Thomas
        instead. Following his death, some of his relics were taken to Edessa while the rest were kept in what is now
        known as India. They can still be found within the San Thome Basilica in Chennai, Mylapore, India.
        \n\n
        Feastday July 3rd / December 21th

    </string>
    <string name="jameslesser">\nJames Lesser, apostle called \"the Younger\" or \"the Just,\" named in the lists of the
        disciples given by Matthew, Mark, and Luke and mentioned in the Acts of the Apostles. He was the son of Alpheus
        and was known as \"the Less\" merely as a means of distinguishing him from James the Greater who was older or
        taller. According to Mark, he stood with the woman Mary and Mary Magdalene at the Crucifixion; he is also called
        by implication the son of the woman Mary. Little else is known with certainty about him, unless one accepts the
        view that he is to be identified with St. James, the Brother of the Lord, with whom he is often confused. In
        liturgical art, he is depicted holding a book or a club. He shares the same feast day as St. Philip.
        \n\n
        Tradition says that James was crucified in Lower Egypt and then sawed in pieces.
        \n\n
        Feastday May 3rd.
    </string>
    <string name="simoncann">\nSimon was surnamed the Zealot for his rigid adherence to the Jewish law and to the
        Canaanite law. He was one of the original followers of Christ. Western tradition is that he preached in Egypt
        and then went to Persia with St. Jude, where both suffered martyrdom. Eastern tradition says Simon died
        peacefully at Edessa.
        \n\n
        Simon the Zealot was a member of the Zealots before he followed Jesus. He is known to be the second bishop of
        Jerusalem, after James the Less. He is said to have been crucified in Samaria after a failed revolt.
        \n\n
        Feast day October 28th.

    </string>
    <string name="matthews">\nHe was the son of Alpheus, and he was likely
        born in Galilee. He worked as a tax collector, which was a hated profession during the time of Christ. According
        to the Gospel, Matthew was working at a collection booth in Capernaum when Christ came to him and asked,
        \"Follow me.\" With this simple call, Matthew became a disciple of Christ.
        \n\n
        From Matthew we know of the many doings of Christ and the message Christ spread of salvation for all people who
        come to God through Him. The Gospel account of Matthew tells the same story as that found in the other three
        Gospels, so scholars are certain of its authenticity. His book is the first of the four Gospels in the New
        Testament. Many years following the death of Christ, around 41 and 50 AD, Matthew wrote his gospel account. He
        wrote the book in Aramaic in the hope that his account would convince his fellow people that Jesus was the
        Messiah and that His kingdom had been fulfilled in a spiritual way. It was an important message at a time when
        almost everyone was expecting the return of a militant messiah brandishing a sword.
        \n\n
        It is thought he departed for other lands to escape persecution sometime after 42 AD. According to various
        legends he fled to Parthia and Persia, or Ethiopia. Nothing is recorded of Matthew\'s passing. We do not know
        how he died, if his death was natural or if he was martyred. Saint Matthew is often depicted with one of the
        four living creatures of Revelation 4:7, which reads, \"The first living creature was like a lion, the second
        like a bull, the third living creature had a human face, and the fourth living creature was like a flying
        eagle.\"
        \n\n
        Matthew, the tax collector, preached in Ethiopia, Judea, Macedonia, Syria and Partha (in northeast Iran).He had
        angered a
        local king who ordered him nailed to a bed, covered his whole body with paper, brimstones, oil, asphalt and
        brushwood and set him on fire.
        \n\n
        Matthew was a tax collector and is therefore the patron saint of bankers.
        \n\n
        Feastday September 21
    </string>
    <string name="judas">\nThe Apostle who betrayed his Divine Master . The name Judas ( Ioudas ) is the Greek form of
        Judah (Hebrew \"praised\"), a proper name frequently found both in the Old and the New Testament. Even among the
        Twelve there were two that bore the name, and for this reason it is usually associated with the surname Iscariot
        [Hebrew \"a man of Kerioth\" or Carioth, which is a city of Judah (cf. Joshua 15:25 )]. There can be no doubt
        that this is the right interpretation of the name, though the true origin is obscured in the Greek spelling,
        and, as might be expected, other derivations have been suggested (e.g. from Issachar).
        \n\n
        Very little is told us in the Sacred Text concerning the history of Judas Iscariot beyond the bare facts of his
        call to the Apostolate, his treachery, and his death. His birthplace, as we have seen, is indicated in his name
        Iscariot, and it may be remarked that his origin separates him from the other Apostles, who were all Galileans.
        For Kerioth is a city of Judah. It has been suggested that this fact may have had some influence on his career
        by causing want of sympathy with his brethren in the Apostolate. We are told nothing concerning the
        circumstances of his call or his share in the ministry and miracles of the Apostles. And it is significant that
        he is never mentioned without some reference to his great betrayal. Thus, in the list of the Apostles given in
        the Synoptic Gospels, we read: \"and Judas Iscariot, who also betrayed him\". ( Matthew 10:4 . Cf. Mark 3:19 ;
        Luke 6:16 ). So again in St. John\'s Gospel the name first occurs in connection with the foretelling of the
        betrayal: \" Jesus answered them: Have not I chosen you twelve; and one of you is a devil? Now he meant Judas
        Iscariot, the son of Simon: for this same was about to betray him whereas he was one of the twelve\" ( John
        6:71-2 )
        \n\n
        We all know how Judas died, hanging himself in remorse for betraying Jesus for 30 pieces of silver.
    </string>
    <string name="domnic">\nDominic Savio (Italian: Domenico Savio; April 2, 1842 – March 9, 1857)
        was an Italian adolescent student of Saint John Bosco. He was studying to be a priest when he became ill and
        died at the age of 14, possibly from pleurisy. He was noted for his piety and devotion to the Catholic faith,
        and was eventually canonized.
    </string>
    <string name="bernadette">\nBernadette was born on 7 January 1844 and baptized at the local parish
        church, St. Pierre\'s, on 9 January, her parents\' wedding anniversary. Bernadette\'s godmother was Bernarde
        Casterot, her mother\'s sister, a moderately wealthy widow who owned a tavern. Hard times had fallen on France
        and the family lived in extreme poverty. Bernadette was a sickly child and possibly due to this only measured
        4ft.7in. tall. She contracted cholera as a toddler and suffered severe asthma for the rest of her life.
        Bernadette attended the day school conducted by the Sisters of Charity and Christian Instruction from
        Nevers.Contrary to a belief popularized by Hollywood movies, St. Bernadette learned very little French, only
        studying French in school after age 13 due to being frequently ill and a poor learner. She could read and write
        very little due to her frequent illness. She spoke the language of Occitan, which was spoken by the local
        population of the Pyrenees region at that time and to a lesser degree today
    </string>
    <string name="tarcisius">\nTarcisius was a martyr of the early Christian church who lived in the 3rd
        century. The little that is known about him comes from a metrical inscription by Pope Damasus I, who was pope in
        the second half of the 4th century.
    </string>
    <string name="maria">\nBorn on October 16 1890 in Corinaldo, in the Ancona Province in Italy,
        her farmworker father moved his family to Ferrier di Conca, near Anzio. When he died of malaria, Maria\'s mother
        had to struggle to feed her children. Maria\'s mother, brothers, and sisters worked in the fields while she
        cooked, sewed, kept the house clean, and watched her youngest sister Teresa. Though the family\'s circumstances
        were extremely difficult, they were very close and loved God.
    </string>
    <string name="philomena">\nLittle is known about the life of St. Philomena. However, it is believed
        she was a Greek princess who became a virgin martyr and died at 13-years-old. Remains of a young lady were
        discovered in May 1802 at the Catacombs of Priscilla on the Via Salaria Nova with three tiles reading Peace be
        to you, Philomena.\' All that is known about St. Philomena\'s life comes from a Neapolitan nun\'s vision. Sister
        Maria Luisa di Gesu claims St. Philomena came to her and told her she was the daughter of a Greek king who
        converted to Christianity. When Philomena was 13-years-old, she took a vow of consecrated virginity.
    </string>
    <string name="agnes">\nA popular saint about whom little is known, Agnes is said to have been a
        beautiful, wealthy Roman maiden who had, in childhood, dedicated herself to God. Some say that a rejected suitor
        betrayed her to authorities; others say that she was asked at 13 to sacrifice to the gods and marry, both of
        which she refused.Legends tell of her being thrown into a brothel, where her purity was miraculously preserved.
        Having escaped that fate, she was martyred. In the IV Century, Constantia, the daughter of Constantine, built a
        basilica on the site of her tomb. St. Ambrose wrote about Agnes in De virginitate, and Damasus I wrote an
        epitaph for her. Prudentius composed a hymn in her honor. Her emblem in art is the lamb because of the
        similarity between her name and the Latin word for lamb, agnus.
    </string>
    <string name="rose_of_viterbo">\nRose of Viterbo, was a young woman born in Viterbo, then a
        contested commune of the Papal States. She spent her brief life as a recluse, who was outspoken in her support
        of the papacy. Otherwise leading an unremarkable life, she later became known for her mystical gifts of
        foretelling the future and having miraculous powers. She is honored as a saint by the Catholic Church.
    </string>
    <string name="imelda">\nThe patroness of fervent first communion, Blessed Imelda, came from
        one of the oldest families in Bologna; her father was Count Igano Lambertini and her mother was Castora Galuzzi.
        Even as a tiny child she showed unusual piety, taking delight in prayer and slipping off to a quiet corner of
        the house, which she adorned with flowers and pictures to make it a little oratory. When she was nine, she was
        placed, at her own wish, in the Dominican convent in Val di Pietra, to be trained there by the nuns. Her
        disposition soon endeared her to all, while the zeal with which she entered all the religious life of the house
        greatly edified the nuns. Her special devotion was to the Eucharistic presence of Our Lord at Mass and in the
        tabernacle. To receive Our Lord in Holy Communion became the consuming desire of her heart, but the custom of
        the place and time had fixed twelve as the earliest age for a first communion. She would sometimes exclaim:
        \"Tell me, can anyone receive Jesus into his heart and not die? \"
    </string>
    <string name="vitus">\nSaint Vitus , according to Christian legend, was a Christian saint from Sicily.
        He died as a martyr during the persecution of Christians by co-ruling Roman Emperors Diocletian and Maximian in
        303 AD. Vitus is counted as one of the Fourteen Holy Helpers of medieval Roman Catholicism. Saint Vitus\' Day is
        celebrated on 15 June. In places where the Julian Calendar is used, this date coincides, in the 20th and 21st
        centuries, with 28 June on the Gregorian Calendar.In the late Middle Ages, people in Germany and countries such
        as Latvia celebrated the feast of Vitus by dancing before his statue.

        Vitus is considered the patron saint of actors, comedians, dancers, and epileptics, similarly to Genesius of
        Rome. He is also said to protect against lightning strikes, animal attacks and oversleeping. Vitus is the patron
        saint of the city of Rijeka in Croatia; the towns of Ciminna in Sicily, Forio on the Island of Ischia, in
        Campania, Italy; the contrada of San Vito, in Torella dei Lombardi, in Avellino, Italy; the town of Winschoten
        in the Netherlands, and the town of St. Vith located in Belgium.
    </string>
    <string name="luis">\nSaint José Luis Sánchez del Río (March 28, 1913 – February 10,
        1928) was a Mexican Cristero who was put to death by government officials because he refused to renounce his
        Catholic faith. His death was seen as a largely political venture on the part of government officials in their
        attempt to stamp out dissent and crush religious freedom in the area. He was dubbed as Joselito. He was declared
        to be martyr on June 22, 2004 by Pope John Paul II and was beatified by Pope Benedict XVI – through the
        Cardinal-Prefect of the Congregation of the Causes of Saints – on November 20, 2005 in Mexico. Pope Francis
        approved a miracle attributed to him on January 21, 2016, allowing for his canonization to take place; a date
        was determined at a consistory on March 15, 2016 and he was proclaimed to be a saint on October 16, 2016.
    </string>
    <string name="crescentius">\nSaint Crescentius of Rome (Italian: San Crescenzio di Roma)
        is venerated as a child martyr by the Roman Catholic Church. According to tradition, he was born of a noble
        Roman family and was baptized along with his parents by Saint Epigmenius. During the persecutions of Christians
        by Diocletian, the family fled to Perugia, where his father Saint Euthymius died. Led back to Rome, Crescentius,
        who was eleven years old, was beheaded on the via Salaria, outside of the city walls.
    </string>
    <string name="mark2">\nBirth:Unknown-Died: 25 April 68 AD much of what we know about St. Mark, the author of the
        Second Gospel, comes largely from the New Testament and early Christian traditions. Mark the Evangelist is
        believed to be the \'John Mark\' referred to in the Acts of the Apostles, the history of the early Church found
        in the Canon of the New Testament. He was the son of Mary of Jerusalem (Acts 12:12) whose home became a meeting
        place for the apostles. He is also the cousin of St. Barnabas (Colossians 4:10), a Levite and a Cypriot. Mark
        joined St. Paul and St. Barnabas on their first missionary journey to Antioch in 44 A.D. When the group reached
        Cyprus, Christian tradition holds that Mark left them and returned to Jerusalem, possibly because he was missing
        his home (Acts 13:13). This incident may have caused Paul to question whether Mark could be a reliable
        missionary. This created a disagreement between Paul and Barnabas and led Paul to refuse Mark\'s accompaniment
        on their second journey to the churches of Cilicia and the rest of Asia Minor. However, it can be assumed the
        troubles between Paul and Mark did not last long, because when Paul was first imprisoned, Mark, who was at the
        time in Rome with plans of visiting Asia Minor, visited him as one of his trusted companions (Col 4:10). Mark\'s
        hopes to visit Asia Minor were most likely carried out, because during Paul\'s second captivity and just before
        his martyrdom, Paul wrote to Timothy at Ephesus advising him to \take Mark and bring him with you [to Rome], for
        he is profitable to me for the ministry (2 Timothy 4:11). If Mark returned to Rome at this time, he was probably
        there when Paul was martyred.
    </string>
    <string name="luke2">\nIt is believed that Luke was born a Greek and a
        Gentile. In Colossians 10-14 speaks of those friends who are with him. He first mentions all those of the
        circumcision — in other words, Jews — and he does not include Luke in this group. Luke\'s gospel shows special
        sensitivity to evangelizing Gentiles. It is only in his gospel that we hear the parable of the Good Samaritan,
        that we hear Jesus praising the faith of Gentiles such as the widow of Zarephath and Naaman the Syrian
        (Lk.4:25-27), and that we hear the story of the one grateful leper who is a Samaritan (Lk.17:11-19). According
        to the early Church historian Eusebius Luke was born at Antioch in Syria. In our day, it would be easy to assume
        that someone who was a doctor was rich, but scholars have argued that Luke might have been born a slave. It was
        not uncommon for families to educate slaves in medicine so that they would have a resident family physician. Not
        only do we have Paul\'s word, but Eusebius, Saint Jerome, Saint Irenaeus and Caius, a second-century writer, all
        refer to Luke as a physician. We have to go to Acts to follow the trail of Luke\'s Christian ministry. We know
        nothing about his conversion but looking at the language of Acts we can see where he joined Saint Paul. The
        story of the Acts is written in the third person, as an historian recording facts, up until the sixteenth
        chapter. In Acts 16:8-9 we hear of Paul\'s company \'So, passing by Mysia, they went down to Troas. During the
        night Paul had a vision: there stood a man of Macedonia pleading with him and saying, \'Come over to Macedonia
        and help us.\' \' Then suddenly in 16:10 they\'/ becomes \'we\': \'When he had seen the vision, we
        immediately tried to cross over to Macedonia, being convinced that God had called us to proclaim the good news
        to them.\'
    </string>
    <string name="paul">
        Saint Paul is one of the most important and influential of all the saints. Many of his writings are contained in
        the Canon of the Bible and have influenced the growth and development of the Church since the first century.
        \n\n
        St. Paul was originally known as Saul, and he was a Roman citizen and a Pharisee. He even presided over the
        persecutions of the early Christians and was present at the martyrdom of St. Stephen. However, Saul experienced
        a powerful vision that caused him to convert to Christianity while on the road to Damascus. He was duly baptized
        and took the name Paul.
        \n\n
        Paul traveled the world, first to Arabia then back to Damascus. He also visited Jerusalem to see St. Peter, the
        first pope and pay homage to him. During these travels, he preached ceaselessly, often drawing criticism and ire
        from those who rebuffed his message. Jews, in particular, hated his preaching as they saw him convert people to
        Christianity from Judaism.
        \n\n
        Eventually, Paul returned to Tarsus, where he was born. He preached there until he was called by Barnabus to
        come to Antioch. After a year spent in Antioch, a famine occurred in Jerusalem and the pair was dispatched to
        the city with alms.
        \n\n
        Paul and Barnabus then went forth on a mission to Cypress and throughout Asia Minor. They established several
        churches in their travels. After establishing his churches, Paul remained in communication with the faithful,
        often writing letters to answer questions and resolve disputes.
        \n\n
        The letters that have survived have become part of the Bible. It is believed that Paul wrote other letters,
        which were lost even before the Bible was established by the Church. Paul\'s writings are important because they
        provide good advice for how Christians should live.
        \n\n
        Paul traveled throughout much of Europe, particularly in Macedonia, Greece, and Italy. While preparing for a
        missionary trip to Spain, he was imprisoned in Caesarea by the Jews for two years. He traveled again, was
        shipwrecked in Malta, and was imprisoned for another two years for preaching in Rome. Despite these
        imprisonments, Paul continued to preach.
        \n\n
        Paul eventually made his way to Spain, then returned to the East, and finally returned to Rome once again. In 67
        AD, Paul was arrested in Rome for a second time and this time he was beheaded under the insane Emperor Nero.
        According to John Chrysostom, Nero knew Paul personally.
        \n\n
        Paul is among the most famous, intelligent and influential of the apostles. There are some who argue that he was
        the leader of the apostles, but this is not supported by the evidence. Instead, he likely preached at the
        request of St. Peter, who was pope.
        \n\n
        St. Paul is the patron saint of missionaries, evangelists, writers, journalists, authors, public workers, rope
        and saddle makers, and tent makers. His feast day is on June 29 when he is honored with Saint Peter, although he
        is also honored on other days throughout the year, January 25, for his conversion, February 16, for his
        shipwreck, and Nov. 18 for the dedication of his Basilica.
    </string>
    <string name="xavier">\nSaint Francis Xavier(1506-1552) was a Navarrese-Basque Roman Catholic missionary born in the
        Kingdom of Navarre on April 7, 1506. His father was a privy counselor and finance minister to King John III of
        Navarre. He was the youngest in his family and resided in a castle which still partially stands today and is in
        the possession of the Jesuit order.
        \n\n
        As the young Francis grew, he was surrounded by war. Navarre was the target of a campaign by King Ferdinand of
        Aragon and Castile, and the kingdom was eventually conquered.
        \n\n
        When the war stopped and Francis came of age, he was sent to study at the University of Paris. While there he
        roomed with his friend, Peter Favre. The pair met and were heavily influenced by Ignatius of Loyola, who
        encouraged Francis to become a priest.
        \n\n
        On August 15, 1534, Francis Xavier along with Peter Favre, and several other friends, made vows of poverty,
        chastity, and obedience. The men planned to travel to the Holy Land to convert non-believers. Francis Xavier
        started his study of theology that same year and was ordained on June 24, 1537.
        \n\n
        Pope Paul III approved the formation of their order in 1540, which became The Society of Jesus. The order is
        more popularly became known as the Jesuits.
        \n\n
        While Francis Xavier was becoming a priest, Portugal was colonizing India. The Portuguese settlers in India and
        elsewhere were losing their faith and Christian values. To restore these values, the King of Portugal asked the
        Pope to send missionaries to the region.
        \n\n
        Pope Paul III asked the new order to take the mission, particularly since they could not undertake their
        preferred mission to the Holy Land due to warfare there. Ignatius ultimately decided to send Francis.
        \n\n
        Francis Xavier left for India in 1541, on his thirty-fifth birthday. As he departed he was informed that the
        pope appointed him to be the Papal Nuncio in the East. A Papal Nuncio is a diplomat who takes up permanent
        residence in another country to formally represent the Church there. He arrived in the region and colony of Goa,
        India on May 6, 1542.
        \n\n
        Although Goa had churches and even a bishop in the Portuguese colony, there were few people to preach and
        minister to the Portuguese, especially outside the walls of the city.
        \n\n
        A major problem Francis quickly recognized was the nature of the people and their intentions. Many sailors and
        settlers were former prisoners who had been recruited from Portuguese jails or were fleeing mistakes they made
        back home. None of them came to spread or live virtuous lives. Instead they came to escape Portugal, find
        adventure, or to make fortunes. Still, they settled and made families.
        \n\n
        Xavier ministered first to the sick and the children. Then he learned about the native people of the Pearl
        Fishery Coast, which had been baptized a decade earlier, but were never taught their faith. Xavier began
        ministering to them. He spent three years among them, but was often embarrassed by the conduct of his Portuguese
        countrymen who were already Catholic, but frequently misbehaved.
        \n\n
        Xavier built 40 churches for the people of the Pearl Fishery Coast. Xavier encountered difficulty in his mission
        because he usually worked to convert the people first, instead of their leaders.
        \n\n
        Xavier returned to Goa for about a year to attend to his official responsibilities, but he was very interested
        in visiting Japan. In 1549, he finally departed for the country, arriving in July of that year.
        \n\n
        He departed India for the last time in April, 1552 and stopped in Malacca to obtain official documents attesting
        to his status as a representative of the Portuguese king. However, the harbor in Malacca was now controlled by
        Alvaro da Gama, the Captain of Malaca and the son of Vasco da Gama.
        \n\n
        Da Gama was not friendly to Xavier who refused to recognize his official status as Papal Nuncio. He confiscated
        the gifts Xavier intended for the Chinese emperor and staffed his ship with a new crew, loyal to himself.
        \n\n
        Xavier\'s ship reached China in August, stopping at an island off the Chinese coast. From there, Xavier was on
        his own. He managed to find a man to agree to take him to China for a large fee, but while he was waiting for
        his boat to arrive became ill with a fever. Xavier died on December 3, 1552.
    </string>
    <string name="gonsalo">\nSaint Gonsalo Garcia (1556–1597) is a Roman Catholic saint from India. Born in the western
        coastal town of Vasai, an exurb of the city of Bombay, he preached from the Bassein fort during the time the
        town was under Portuguese colonial rule. The feast of St. Garcia has traditionally been held on the first Sunday
        nearest to the neap tide following Christmas in Vasai. Gonsalo Garcia was born Gundi Slavus Garcia— to a
        Portuguese father and a Canarese (resident of the Konkan coast) mother in Bassein, on February 5, 1557. He was
        the right hand of father St. Peter Baptist Superior of Franciscan mission in Japan. He was tutored by Fr.
        Sebastian Gonçalves, a Jesuit priest working in Vasai, in the college near Bassein fort. Garcia studied under
        the tutelage of the Jesuits for eight years from 1564 to 157
        2. Then, at the age of fifteen, Fr. Sebastian took
        Garcia to Japan. He soon managed to learn the language and since was seen as an affable person; he soon became
        popular in the local community as a catechist. He resigned and left to Alcao to set up trade. His business
        prospered and branches were opened in different locales in Southeast Asia.
    </string>
    <string name="anthony">
        Saint Anthony was born Fernando Martins in Lisbon, Portugal. He was born into a wealthy family and by the age of
        fifteen asked to be sent to the Abbey of Santa Cruz in Coimbra, the then capital of Portugal. During his time in
        the Abbey, he learned theology and Latin.
        \n\n
        Following his ordination to the priesthood, he was named guestmaster and was responsible for the abbey\'s
        hospitality. When Franciscan friars settled a small hermitage outside Coimbra dedicated to Saint Anthony of
        Egypt, Fernando felt a longing to join them.
        \n\n
        Fernando eventually received permission to leave the Abbey so he could join the new Franciscan Order. When he
        was admitted, he changed his name to Anthony.
        \n\n
        Anthony then traveled to Morocco to spread God\'s truth, but became extremely sick and was returned to Portugal
        to recover. The return voyage was blown off-course and the party arrived in Sicily, from which they traveled to
        Tuscany. Athony was assigned to the hermitage of San Paolo after local friars considered his health.
        \n\n
        As he recovered, Anthony spent his time praying and studying.An undetermined amount of time later, Dominican
        friars came to visit the Franciscans and there was confusion over who would present the homily. The Dominicans
        were known for their preaching, thus the Franciscans assumed it was they who would provide a homilist, but the
        Dominicans assumed the Franciscans would provide one. It was then the head of the Franciscan hermitage asked
        Anthony to speak on whatever the Holy Spirit told him to speak of.
        \n\n
        Though he tried to object, Anthony delivered an eloquent and moving homily that impressed both groups. Soon,
        news of his eloquence reached Francis of Assisi, who held a strong distrust of the brotherhood\'s commitment to
        a life of poverty. However, in Anthony, he found a friend.
        \n\n
        In 1224, Francis entrusted his friars\' pursuits of studies to Anthony. Anthony had a book of psalms that
        contained notes and comments to help when teaching students and, in a time when a printing press was not yet
        invented, he greatly valued it.
        \n\n
        When a novice decided to leave the hermitage, he stole Anthony\'s valuable book. When Anthony discovered it was
        missing, he prayed it would be found or returned to him. The thief did return the book and in an extra step
        returned to the Order as well. The book is said to be preserved in the Franciscan friary in Bologna today.
        \n\n
        Anthony occasionally taught at the universities of Montpellier and Toulouse in southern France, but he performed
        best in the role of a preacher. So simple and resounding was his teaching of the Catholic Faith, most unlettered
        and the innocent could understand his messages. It is for this reason he was declared a Doctor of the Church by
        Pope Pius XII in 1946.
        \n\n
        Once, when St. Anthony of Padua attempted to preach the true Gospel of the Catholic Church to heretics who would
        not listen to him, he went out and preached his message to the fish. This was not, as liberals and naturalists
        have tried to say, for the instruction of the fish, but rather for the glory of God, the delight of the angels,
        and the easing of his own heart. When critics saw the fish begin to gather, they realized they should also
        listen to what Anthony had to say.
        \n\n
        He was only 35-years-old when he died and was canonized less than one year afterward by Pope Gregory IX. Upon
        exhumation some 336 years after his death, his body was found to be corrupted, yet his tongue was totally
        incorrupt, so perfect were the teachings that had been formed upon it.
        \n\n
        He is typically depicted with a book and the Infant Child Jesus and is commonly referred to today as the
        \"finder of lost articles.\"
        \n\n
        St Anthony is venerated all over the world as the Patron Saint for lost articles, and is credited with many
        miracles involving lost people, lost things and even lost spiritual goods.

    </string>
    <string name="theresa">\nThe remarkable woman who would be known as Mother Theresa began life named Agnes Gonxha
        Bojaxhiu. Born on August 26, 1910 in Skopje, she was the youngest child born to Nikola and Drane Bojaxhiu,
        Receiving her First Communion at the age of five, she was confirmed in November 1916.Gonxha\'s religious
        formation was assisted by the vibrant Jesuit parish of the Sacred Heart in which she was very involved as a
        youth. Institute of the Blessed Virgin Mary, known as the Sisters of Loreto, in Ireland. She received the name
        Sister Mary Teresa after St. Therese of Lisieux. In December of 1929, she departed for her first trip to India,
        arriving in Calcutta. in May 1931, Sister Teresa was assigned to the Loreto Entally community in CalcuttaSister
        Teresa made her Final Profession of Vows, On May 24, 1937, becoming, as she said, the spouse of Jesus for all
        eternity.From that time on she was called Mother Teresa.
    </string>
    <string name="alphonso">\nShe was born as Annakkutty (little Anna) in Kudamaloor, a village in the princely state of
        Travancore which was under the British Raj to Joseph and Mary Muttathupadathu.
        \n\n
        Anna arrived at the Clarist convent at Bharananganam, Kottayam district, on Pentecost Sunday 1927.She received
        the postulant\'s veil on 2 August 1928 and took the name Alphonsa of the Immaculate Conception in honor of St.
        Alphonsus Liguori, whose feast day it was.In May 1929 Sister Alphonsa was assigned to teach at Malayalam High
        School at Vazhappally. Her foster mother died in 1930. She resumed her studies at Changanacherry, while working
        as a temporary teacher at a school at Vakakkad
        \n\n
        On 19 May 1930 she received her religious habit at Bharananganam. Three days later she resumed her studies at
        Changanacherry, while working as a
        temporary teacher at the school at Vakakkad. On 11 August 1931 she joined the novitiate. Anna took her permanent
        vows on 12 August 1936. Two days later she returned to Bharananganam from Changanacherry.She taught elementary
        school, but was often sick and unable to teach.

        \n\n
        In December 1936, it is claimed that she was cured from her ailments through the intervention of Blessed
        Kuriakose Elias Chavara, but on 14 June 1939 she was struck by a
        severe attack of pneumonia, which left her weakened.
        \n
        Her health continued to deteriorate over a period of months. She received extreme unction on 29 September 1941.
        The next day it is believed that she regained her memory, though not complete health. Her health improved over
        the next few years, until in July 1945 she developed gastroenteritis and liver problems that caused violent
        convulsions and vomiting.During the last year of her life she came to know Father Sebastian Valopilly (later
        Bishop of Kerala) who frequently brought her communion. This bishop became famous in Kerala for championing the
        cause of poor people from all religious backgrounds who had come to live in Thalassery as a result of shortages
        elsewhere.
        \n\n
        She died on 28 July 1946, aged 35. She is buried at
        Bharananganam, Travancore (present day Kerala) in the Diocese of Palai.Her health continued to deteriorate over
        a period of months.
    </string>
    <string name="pio">\nSt. Padre Pio was an Italian priest who was known for his piety and charity, as well as the
        gift
        of the stigmata, which has never been explained. St. Padre Pio was born Francesco Forgione, on May 25, 1887, in
        Pietrelcina, Italy. His parents were peasant farmers.
        \n\n
        From his tender age, Francisco had a peculiar ability. He could see guardian angels, spoke with Jesus and the
        Virgin Mary. This was not something taught to him, but occurred so naturally that he assumed other people could
        see them too.
        \n\n
        Francisco was sickly as a child. He suffered an attack of gastroenteritis at age six and when he was ten, he had
        typhoid fever.
        \n\n
        In 1897, after three years of schooling, Francisco expressed to his parents that he wanted to become a friar.
        His parents traveled to a nearby community of monks and asked if Francesco could join them. He was evaluated,
        despite his young age, and was told that he needed more education before he could join. To prepare Francesco,
        his parents decided to hire a private tutor. To pay the cost of the tutor, Francesco\'s father traveled to
        America to find work, and sent the money home. At the age of 15, Francisco was finally ready and he entered the
        novitiate of the Capuchin friars at Morcone. He took the name of \"Pio\" in honor of Pope Pius I, whose relic he
        often saw at his local chapel.
        \n\n
        At the age of 17, Brother Pio became extremely ill and could only digest milk and cheese. He was sent to the
        mountain for better air, and when this did not work, he was sent home to his family. Amid all this, he continued
        to study for the priesthood. On one occasion during prayer, a fellow monk astonishingly reported he saw Pio
        levitate during an episode of ecstasy. Brother Pio became a priest in 1910, but was permitted to remain at home
        because of his poor health.
        \n\n
        On September 20, Padre Pio was hearing confessions when he felt pain in his hands and feet. He noticed the
        stigmata, the wounds of Christ, appearing on his hands and feet. The experience was painful. Bleeding occurred.
        The wounds smelled of roses, and although they continued to weep, they never became infected. Doctors who later
        examined the stigmata were amazed at their perfectly round shape. By 1919, word began to spread about Padre
        Pio\'s stigmata and people came from far away to examine him. Padre Pio became popular with the people he
        encountered and soon began to attribute supernatural occurrences to him. For example, he was said to levitate,
        and able to perform miracles.
        \n\n
        His popularity became a source of concern for the Church and the Vatican began to restrict his activities to
        minimize public interaction. Padre Pio himself was uncomfortable with his newfound popularity and the attention
        he received because of his stigmata. A Church investigation into his stigmata concluded that his condition was
        not faked. By 1934, the Vatican began to change its attitude towards Padre Pio and he was again allowed to
        perform public duties. He could preach, despite never being officially licensed by the Church to do so. Pope
        Pius XI encouraged people to visit him.
        \n\n
        Padre Pio became internationally famous. He was known for his piety, charity and the quality of his preaching.
        He famously advised, \"Pray, hope and don\'t worry.\" He had other illnesses, as well, including cancer which
        was miraculously healed after just two treatments. Other problems, such as arthritis, which plagued him in his
        later years, never went away. Padre Pio died on September 23, 1968. His funeral was attended by over 100,000
        people.
        \n\n
        He is a patron of civil defence volunteers, adolescents.
        \n\n
        He was recognized as a saint on 16 June 2002 by Pope John Paul 2.
        \n\n
        Feastday 23 September


    </string>
    <string name="mary">\nSt. Mary Magdalene is one of the greatest saints of the Bible and a legendary example of
        God\'s
        mercy and grace. The precise dates of her birth and death are unknown, but we do know she was present with
        Christ during his public ministry, death and resurrection.
        \n\n
        She is mentioned at least a dozen times in the
        Gospels.The Gospels agree that Mary was originally a great sinner. Jesus cast seven demons out of her when he
        met her. After this, she told several women she associated with and these women also became followers.
        \n\n
        During Jesus\' ministry, it is believed that Mary Magdalene followed him, part of a semi-permanent entourage who
        served Jesus and his Disciples.
        \n\n
        Mary likely watched the crucifixion from a distance along with the other women who followed Christ during His
        ministry. Mary was present when Christ rose from the dead, visiting his tomb to anoint his body only to find the
        stone rolled away and Christ, very much alive, sitting at the place they laid Him. She was the first witness to
        His resurrection.
        \n\n
        After the death of Christ, a legend states that she remained among the early Christians. After fourteen years,
        she was allegedly put into a boat by Jews, along with several other saints of the early Church, and set adrift
        without sails or oars. The boat landed in southern France, where she spent the remaining years of her life
        living in solitude, in a cave.
        \n\n
        She is the patroness of converts, repentant sinners, sexual temptation, pharmacists, tanners and women, and many
        other places and causes.
        \n\n
        Feastday July 22th.
    </string>
    <string name="fastina">\nSaint Maria Faustina Kowalska of the Blessed Sacrament was born as Helena Kowalska, in
        Glogowiec, Leczyca County, north-west of Lódz in Poland on August 25, 1905. She was the third of 10 children to
        a poor and religious family. Faustina first felt a calling to the religious life when she was just
        seven-years-old and attended the Exposition of the Blessed Sacrament. After finishing her schooling, Faustina
        wanted to immediately join a convent. However, her parents refused to let her. Instead, at 16-years-old,
        Faustina became a housekeeper to help her parents and support herself. In 1924, Faustina experienced her first
        vision of Jesus. While at a dance with her sister, Natalia, Faustina saw a suffering Jesus and then went to a
        Cathedral. According to Faustina, Jesus instructed her to leave for Warsaw immediately and join a convent.
        Faustina packed her bags at once and departed the following morning. When she arrived in Warsaw, she entered
        Saint James Church in Warsaw, the first church she came across, and attended Mass.
    </string>
    <string name="teresa">\nTeresa died when she was 24, after having lived as cloistered Carmelite for less than ten
        years. She never went on missions, never founded a religious order, never performed great works. The only book
        of hers, published after her death, was an brief edited version of her journal called /\'Story of a Soul.\'/
        (Collections of her letters and restored versions of her journals have been published recently.) But within 28
        years of her death, the public demand was so great that she was canonized. Over the years, some modern Catholics
        have turned away from her because they associate her with over- sentimentalized piety and yet the message she
        has for us is still as compelling and simple as it was almost a century ago. Therese was born in France in 1873,
        the pampered daughter of a mother who had wanted to be a saint and a father who had wanted to be monk. The two
        had gotten married but determined they would be celibate until a priest told them that was not how God wanted a
        marriage to work! They must have followed his advice very well because they had nine children. The five children
        who lived were all daughters who were close all their lives.
    </string>
    <string name="apostle">Apostles\' Creed</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="thaddeus">\nSt. Jude, known as Thaddaeus, was a brother of St. James the Less, and a relative of Our
        Saviour.
        He was one of the 12 Apostles of Jesus.
        \n\n
        Biblical scholars agree St. Jude was a son of Clopas and his mother Mary was the Virgin Mary\'s cousin. Ancient
        writers tell us that he preached the Gospel in Judea, Samaria, Idumaea, Syria, Mesopotamia, and Libya. According
        to Eusebius, he returned to Jerusalem in the year 62, and assisted at the election of his brother, St. Simeon,
        as Bishop of Jerusalem.
        \n\n
        He is an author of an epistle (letter) to the Churches of the East, particularly the Jewish converts, directed
        against the heresies of the Simonians, Nicolaites, and Gnostics.The Apostles Jude and Bartholomew are believed
        to have brought
        Christianity to Armenia, where Jude was rumored to have later been martyred.
        \n\n
        Following his death, St. Jude\'s body was brought to Rome and left in a crypt in St. Peter\'s Basilica. Today
        his bones can be found in the left transept of St. Peter\'s Basilica under the main altar of St. Joseph in a
        tomb he shares with the remains of the apostle Simon the Zealot.
        \n\n
        Roman Catholics invoke St. Jude when in desperate situations because his New Testament letter stresses that the
        faithful should persevere in the environment of harsh, difficult circumstances -just as their forefathers had
        done before them; therefore, he is the patron saint of desperate cases.
        \n\n
        There are several sites across the world dedicated to the Apostle Jude, including shrines and
        churches. The National Shrine of Saint Jude was founded in 1955 and can be found in England.
        \n\n
        In India there is St.Jude\'s shrine in Jhansi
        \n\n
        Thaddaeus was martyred in Persia by arrows.
        \n\n
        Feastday October 28th
    </string>
    <string name="email_title">Feedback on Angels and Saints app</string>
    <string name="Nicene_creed">Nicene Creed</string>
    <string name="nicene_creed">I believe in one God, the Father Almighty, Maker of heaven and
        earth, and of all things visible and invisible. And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only-begotten Son of God,
        begotten of the Father before all worlds; God of God, Light of Light, very God of very God; begotten, not made,
        being of one substance with the Father, by whom all things were made. Who, for us men for our salvation, came
        down from heaven, and was incarnate by the Holy Spirit of the virgin Mary, and was made man; and was crucified
        also for us under Pontius Pilate; He suffered and was buried; and the third day He rose again, according to the
        Scriptures; and ascended into heaven, and sits on the right hand of the Father; and He shall come again, with
        glory, to judge the quick and the dead; whose kingdom shall have no end. And I believe in the Holy Spirit, the
        Lord and Giver of Life; who proceeds from the Father [and the Son]; who with the Father and the Son together is
        worshipped and glorified; who spoke by the prophets. And I believe one holy catholic and apostolic Church. I
        acknowledge one baptism for the remission of sins; and I look for the resurrection of the dead, and the life of
        the world to come.
        \n\n
        Amen.\n\n\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="nicene_mar">नायसियन क्रीड\n\nस्वर्ग आणि पृथ्वी सर्व दृश्य व अदृश्य वस्तू ह्यांचा उत्पन्नकर्ता । एकच
        परमेश्वर, सर्वशक्तिमान
        पिता । ह्यावर मी श्रद्धा ठेवतो । आणि परमेश्वराचा एकुलता एक पुत्र । येशू ख्रिस्त एकच प्रभू । ह्यावर मी श्रद्धा
        ठेवतो तो सर्व युगांपूर्वी पित्यापासून जन्मलेला आहे । परमेश्वरापासून परमेश्वर। प्रकाशापासून प्रकाश । खऱ्या
        परमेश्वरापासून खरा परमेश्वर तो पित्याशी एकतत्त्व असून । जन्मलेला आहे उत्पन्न केलेला नाही । त्याजकडून सर्व
        उत्पन्न झाले आहे । तो आम्हा मानवांसाठी । व आमच्या तारणासाठी । स्वर्गातून उतरला । तो पवित्र आत्म्याच्या योगाने ।
        कुमारी मरियेपासून । शरीर धारण करून । मनुष्य झाला । शिवाय आम्हासाठी त्याला क्रुसी दिले । पोन्ती पिलाताच्या
        अमदानीत। त्याने दुःख भोगले । तो मरण पावला । त्याला पुरले । तो अधोलोकांत उतरला । शास्त्राप्रमाणे तो तिसऱ्या दिवशी
        पुन्हा जिवंत झाला । व स्वर्गात चढला आणि पित्याच्या उजवीकडे बसला आहे । आणि जिवंतांचा व मृतांचा न्याय करावयास ।
        वैभवाने पुन्हा येणार आहे । त्याच्या राज्याचा शेवट होणार नाही । आणि पवित्र आत्मा । प्रभू व जीवनदाता । यावर मी
        श्रद्धा ठेवतो । तो पिता आणि पुत्र यांपासून निघतो। आणि पिता व पुत्र । यांसहित त्याला भजतात व त्याचा गौरव करतात ।
        तो संदेष्ट्यांमार्फत बोलला आहे । आणि एकाच, पवित्र, कॅथोलिक व प्रेषितीय ख्रिस्तसभेवर । मी श्रद्धा ठेवतो ।
        पापक्षमेसाठी मी एक बाप्तिस्मा मान्य करतो । आणि मेलेल्यांचे पुनरूत्थान । व भावी जगातील जीवनाची । मी वाट पाहतो ।
        \n\n आमेन.
    </string>
    <string name="Principle">\nThe seventh highest order of angels Principalities possess.\"princely Powers\" and
        watch over the actions of the earth\'s nations and cities the visible world of humankind. Every nation has its
        own Principality. They also govern and protect religion on this planet. Principalities can help humans call upon
        secret powers to subdue others and establish their own authority.
        Principalities are linked to the element of air. They are sometimes equated with the Elohim. They rule Netzach
        (victory), the seventh sephirot of the Tree of Life. Their chiefs are Requel, Anael, Cerviel, and Nisroc.
        1 Enoch 61/10, links principalities with other high ranking angels the cherubim, seraphim, ophanim, \"and all
        the angels of power.\"
        Principalities appear as soldiers with two wings, golden belts, and lance - headed javelins. They wear princely
        robes over armour, with crowns and sword or scepter.
        \n\n<b>Mission</b>\n\nThey protect the kingdom of God and give us the spirit of Obedience.
    </string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="prayer_holyspirit">
        PRAYER TO THE HOLY SPIRIT
        \n \n Come, Holy SPIRIT, fill the hearts of your faithful, and kindle in them the fire of your love.\n \n V.
        Send forth your Spirit and they shall be created;\n \n R. And you shall renew the face of the earth.\n \n Let
        us pray.
        \n\n O God who didst instruct the hearts of your faithful by the light of the Holy Spirit, grant that, by the
        same Spirit, we may be truly wise, and ever rejoice in His consolation. Through Christ, our Lord.
        Amen.
    </string>
    <string name="carlo">
        \nBlessed Carlo Acutis was born on May 3, 1991 in London, United Kingdom to Andrea Acutis and Antonia Salzano.
        His parents were financially well-off and worked in Germany and the United Kingdom before settling down in
        Milan, Italy in September 1991.
        \n\n
        From a young age, around 3, he demonstrated great interest in Catholic churches and often asked to see them. At
        the age of 7 he received his First holy Communion at the convent of St. Amdrogio and Nemus. He was commonly
        observed praying before the Tabernacle before and after Mass. He also went to Confession once per week. He
        enjoyed visiting Assisi where St. Francis is entombed.
        \n\n
        In addition to his love for the Church, Acutis was deeply interested in computers and taught himself how to code
        and build websites while still in primary school. His brief high school career was spent in the care of the
        Jesuits at the Institute of Leo XIII.
        \n\n
        Acutis was also known to give away his pocket money to the poor and to speak up in defense of the disabled. He
        had a habit of inviting kids to his house whose parents were divorcing to support them. Acutis used his
        knowledge of computers and coding to build websites for Catholic organizations. His most popular website was one
        that listed miracles from around the world based on a catalog he compiled since age 11. He completed the site
        shortly before his death. When Acutis developed leukemia as a teenager, he offered up his suffering for Pope
        Benedict XVI and the Church. He was quoted as saying, \"I offer all the suffering I will have to suffer for the
        Lord, the Pope, and the Church.\" As part of his devotion, Acutis asked his parents to take him to various
        Eucharistic shrines, although his declining health made travel increasingly difficult.
        \n\n
        Acutis died in on October 12, 2006 at age 15, in Monza, Italy.
        \n\n
        Exactly four years following his death, his mother gave birth to twins which she attributed to her son\'s
        intercession. She also said her son has appeared to her in dreams foretelling his canonization. Carlo Acutis was
        labeled a \"Servant of God\" in 2013, one of the first steps towards canonization. A miracle was attributed to
        him in November of 2019. In that miracle, a seven-year-old child who was born with a pancreatic defect was
        miraculously healed. She prayed to Acutis, asking for his intercession and shortly after, the defect was
        miraculously cured.
        \n\n
        Pope Francis announced the beatification of Carlo Acutis while visiting Assisi, Italy on October 10. He made
        another announcement on October 11, during his Angelus prayer.
        \n\n
        Carlo Acutis\'s feast day is October 12, and he is a patron for computer programmers and youth.
    </string>
    <string name="joseph">
        As Mary was from eternity predestined to be the mother of the Son of God; so also was Joseph elected to be the
        guardian and protector of Jesus and of Mary.
        In order to safeguard the reputation of the Virgin Mother and the honour of the Divine Son, God willed that Mary
        by a marriage altogether heavenly should be espoused to the humblest, the purest, and the holiest of the royal
        race of David, a virgin spouse for the Virgin Mother, who at the same time should be in the place of a father to
        the Divine Son. Joseph was a righteous man\" (Matthew 1:18).
        St Joseph, after Jesus and Mary is superior to all the other Saints, both of the Old and the New Testament.
        \n\n
        An angel came to Joseph in a dream and told him, 20 \"Joseph son of David, do not be afraid to take Mary home as
        your wife, because what is conceived in her is from the Holy Spirit. 21 She will give birth to a son, and you
        are to give him the name Jesus, because he will save his people from their sins,\" he did as the angel told him
        and took Mary as his wife. (Matthew 1:19-25).
        \n\n
        Angel came again to tell him that his family was in danger, he immediately left everything he owned, all his
        family and friends, and fled to a strange country with his young wife and the baby. He waited in Egypt without
        question until the angel told him it was safe to go back (Matthew 2:13-23)
        \n\n
        When Jesus stayed in the Temple we are told Joseph (along with Mary) searched with great anxiety for three days
        for him (Luke 2:48). We also know that Joseph treated Jesus as his own son for over and over the people of
        Nazareth say of Jesus, \"Is this not the son of Joseph?\" (Luke 4:22)
        \n\n
        We know Joseph respected God. He followed God\'s commands in handling the situation with Mary and going to
        Jerusalem to have Jesus circumcised and Mary purified after Jesus\' birth. We are told that he took his family
        to Jerusalem every year for Passover, something that could not have been easy for a working man.
        Joseph is the patron saint of the dying because, assuming he died before Jesus\' public life, he died with Jesus
        and Mary close to him, the way we all would like to leave this earth
        \n\n
        Joseph is also patron saint of the Universal Church, families, fathers, expectant mothers (pregnant women),
        travelers, immigrants, house sellers and buyers, craftsmen, engineers, and working people in general.
        We celebrate two feast days for Joseph: March 19 for Joseph the Husband of Mary and May 1 for Joseph the Worker.
        March 19 has been the most commonly celebrated feast day for Joseph, and it wasn\'t until 1955 that Pope Pius
        XII established the Feast of \"St. Joseph the Worker\" to be celebrated on May 1. This is also May Day
        (International Workers\' Day) and believed to reflect Joseph\'s status as the patron of workers.
        \n\n
        Many places and churches all over the world are named after St. Joseph, including the Spanish form, San Jose,
        which is the most commonly named place in the world. Joseph is considered by many to also be the patron saint of
        the New World; of the countries China, Canada, Korea, Mexico, Austria, Belgium, Croatia, Peru, Vietnam; of the
        regions Carinthia, Styria, Tyrol, Sicily; and of several main cities and dioceses.
        \n\n
        Some statues of Joseph show his staff topped with flowers. St. Joseph is shown with the attributes of a
        carpenter\'s square or tools, the infant Jesus, his lily blossomed staff, two turtle doves, or a spikenard.
        \n\n
        Prayer:\n
        Saint Joseph, patron of the universal Church, watch over the Church as carefully as you watched over Jesus, help
        protect it and guide it as you protected your son Jesus. Amen
    </string>
    <string name="clare">
        \n\n
        St. Clare of Assisi was born in Assisi on July 16, 1194, as Chiara Offreduccio, the beautiful eldest daughter of
        Favorino Sciffi, Count of Sasso-Rosso and his wife Ortolana. Tradition says her father was a wealthy
        representative of an ancient Roman family and her mother was a very devout woman belonging to the noble family
        of Fiumi.
        \n\n
        As a young girl, Clare dedicated herself to prayer. At 18-years-old, she heard St. Francis of Assisi preach
        during a Lenten service in the church of San Giorgio and asked him to help her live according to the Gospel. On
        Palm Sunday in 1212, Clare left her father\'s home and went to the chapel of the Porziuncula to meet with
        Francis. While there, Clare\'s hair was cut off and she was given a plain robe and veil in exchange for her rich
        gown.
        \n\n
        Clare joined the convent of the Benedictine nuns of San Paulo, near Bastia, under Francis\' orders. When her
        father found her and attempted to force her back into his home, she refused and professed that she would have no
        other husband than Jesus Christ. In order to give her the greater solitude she desired, Francis sent Clare to
        Sant\' Angelo in Panzo, another Benedictine nuns monastery.
        \n\n
        In 1224, an army of rough soldiers from Frederick II came to attack Assisi. Although very sick, Clare went out
        to meet them with the Blessed Sacrament on her hands. She had the Blessed Sacrament placed at the wall where the
        enemies could see it. Then on her knees, she begged God to save the Sisters.
        \n\n
        \"O Lord, protect these Sisters whom I cannot protect now,\" she prayed. A voice seemed to answer: \"I will keep
        them always in My care.\" In that moment, a sudden fright struck the attackers and they fled as fast as they
        could without harming anyone in Assisi.
        \n\n
        St. Clare became sick and suffered great pains for many years, but she expressed that no pain could trouble her.
        So great was her joy in serving the Lord that she once exclaimed: \"They say that we are too poor, but can a
        heart which possesses the infinite God be truly called poor?\"
        \n\n
        On August 9, 1253, Pope Innocent IV declared Clare\'s rule would serve as the governing rule for Clare\'s Order
        of Poor Ladies. Two days later, Clare died at 59-years-old. Her remains were placed in the chapel of San Giorgio
        while the church dedicated to her remains was being built. At Pope Innocent\'s request, the canonization process
        for Clare began immediately, and two years later in 1255, Pope Alexander IV canonized Clare as Saint Clare of
        Assisi.
        \n\n
        The construction of the Basilica of Saint Clare was finished in 1260, and on October 3, 1260 Clare\'s remains
        were transferred there and buried beneath the high altar. Nearly 600 years later, her remains were transferred
        once again to a newly constructed shrine in the crypt of the Basilica of Saint Clare. Her body is no longer
        claimed to be incorrupt.
        \n\n
        St. Clare was designated as the patron saint of television in 1958 by Pope Pius XII, because when St. Clare was
        very ill, she could not attend mass and was reportedly able to see and hear it on the wall in her room. She is
        also the patroness of eye disease, goldsmiths, and laundry.
        \n\n
        Clare is often pictured carrying a monstrance or pyx, to commemorate the time she warded off the soldiers at the
        gates of her convent with the Blessed Sacrament.
        \n\n
        St. Clare\'s feast day is celebrated on August 11.
    </string>
    <string name="francisassisi">
        \n\n
        Founder of the Franciscan Order, born at Assisi in Umbria, in 1181.
        \n\n
        Francis enjoyed a very rich easy life growing up because of his father\'s wealth and the permissiveness of the
        times. As he grew up, Francis became the leader of a crowd of young people who spent their nights in wild
        parties. Thomas of Celano, his biographer who knew him well, said, \"In other respects an exquisite youth, he
        attracted to himself a whole retinue of young people addicted to evil and accustomed to vice.\" Francis himself
        said, \"I lived in sin\" during that time.
        \n\n
        Francis was also good at business. But Francis wanted more..more than wealth. But not holiness!. Assisi declared
        war on their longtime enemy, the nearby town of Perugia.
        \n\n
        But Francis never got farther than one day\'s ride from Assisi. There he had a dream in which God told him he
        had it all wrong and told him to return home. And return home he did. What must it have been like to return
        without ever making it to battle — the boy who wanted nothing more than to be liked was humiliated, laughed at,
        called a coward by the village and raged at by his father for the money wasted on armor.
        \n\n
        Francis\' conversion did not happen over night. God had waited for him for twenty-five years and now it was
        Francis\' turn to wait. Francis started to spend more time in prayer. He went off to a cave and wept for his
        sins. Sometimes God\'s grace overwhelmed him with joy. But life couldn\'t just stop for God. There was a
        business to run, customers to wait on.
        \n\n
        One day while riding through the countryside, Francis, the man who loved beauty, who was so picky about food,
        who hated deformity, came face to face with a leper. Repelled by the appearance and the smell of the leper,
        Francis nevertheless jumped down from his horse and kissed the hand of the leper. When his kiss of peace was
        returned, Francis was filled with joy. As he rode off, he turned around for a last wave, and saw that the leper
        had disappeared. He always looked upon it as a test from God…that he had passed.
        \n\n
        His search for conversion led him to the ancient church at San Damiano. While he was praying there, he heard
        Christ on the crucifix speak to him, \"Francis, repair my church.\" Francis assumed this meant church with a
        small c — the crumbling building he was in. Acting again in his impetuous way, he took fabric from his
        father\'s shop and sold it to get money to repair the church. His father saw this as an act of theft — and put
        together with Francis\' cowardice, waste of money, and his growing disinterest in money made Francis seem more
        like a madman than his son. Pietro dragged Francis before the bishop and in front of the whole town demanded
        that Francis return the money and renounce all rights as his heir.
        \n\n
        The bishop was very kind to Francis; he told him to return the money and said God would provide. That was all
        Francis needed to hear. He not only gave back the money but stripped off all his clothes — the clothes his
        father had given him — until he was wearing only a hair shirt. In front of the crowd that had gathered he said,
        \"Pietro Bernardone is no longer my father. From now on I can say with complete freedom, \'Our Father who art in
        heaven.\'\" Wearing nothing but castoff rags, he went off into the freezing woods — singing. And when robbers
        beat him later and took his clothes, he climbed out of the ditch and went off singing again. From then on
        Francis had nothing…and everything.
        \n\n
        Francis went back to what he considered God\'s call. He begged for stones and rebuilt the San Damiano church
        with his own hands, not realizing that it was the Church with a capital C that God wanted repaired. Scandal and
        avarice were working on the Church from the inside while outside heresies flourished by appealing to those
        longing for something different or adventurous.
        \n\n
        Soon Francis started to preach. (He was never a priest, though he was later ordained a deacon under his
        protest.) Francis was not a reformer; he preached about returning to God and obedience to the Church. Francis
        must have known about the decay in the Church, but he always showed the Church and its people his utmost
        respect. When someone told him of a priest living openly with a woman and asked him if that meant the Mass was
        polluted, Francis went to the priest, knelt before him, and kissed his hands — because those hands had held
        God.
        \n\n
        Slowly companions came to Francis, people who wanted to follow his life of sleeping in the open, begging for
        garbage to eat…and loving God. With companions, Francis knew he now had to have some kind of direction to this
        life so he opened the Bible in three places. He read the command to the rich young man to sell all his good and
        give to the poor, the order to the apostles to take nothing on their journey, and the demand to take up the
        cross daily. \"Here is our rule,\" Francis said — as simple, and as seemingly impossible, as that. He was going
        to do what no one thought possible any more — live by the Gospel. Francis took these commands so literally that
        he made one brother run after the thief who stole his hood and offer him his robe!
        \n\n
        Francis never wanted to found a religious order — this former knight thought that sounded too military. He
        thought of what he was doing as expressing God\'s brotherhood. His companions came from all walks of life, from
        fields and towns, nobility and common people, universities, the Church, and the merchant class. Francis
        practiced true equality by showing honor, respect, and love to every person whether they were beggar or pope.
        \n\n
        Francis\' brotherhood included all of God\'s creation. Much has been written about Francis\' love of nature but
        his relationship was deeper than that. We call someone a lover of nature if they spend their free time in the
        woods or admire its beauty. But Francis really felt that nature, all God\'s creations, were part of his
        brotherhood. The sparrow was as much his brother as the pope.
        \n\n
        In one famous story, Francis preached to hundreds of birds about being thankful to God for their wonderful
        clothes, for their independence, and for God\'s care. The story tells us the birds stood still as he walked
        among him, only flying off when he said they could leave.
        \n\n
        Another famous story involves a wolf that had been eating human beings. Francis intervened when the town wanted
        to kill the wolf and talked the wolf into never killing again. The wolf became a pet of the townspeople who made
        sure that he always had plenty to eat.
        \n\n
        Following the Gospel literally, Francis and his companions went out to preach two by two. At first, listeners
        were understandably hostile to these men in rags trying to talk about God\'s love. People even ran from them for
        fear they\'d catch this strange madness! And they were right. Because soon these same people noticed that these
        barefoot beggars wearing sacks seemed filled with constant joy. They celebrated life. And people had to ask
        themselves: Could one own nothing and be happy? Soon those who had met them with mud and rocks, greeted them
        with bells and smiles.
        \n\n
        Francis did not try to abolish poverty, he tried to make it holy. When his friars met someone poorer than they,
        they would eagerly rip off the sleeve of their habit to give to the person. They worked for all necessities and
        only begged if they had to. But Francis would not let them accept any money. He told them to treat coins as if
        they were pebbles in the road. When the bishop showed horror at the friars\' hard life, Francis said, \"If we
        had any possessions we should need weapons and laws to defend them.\" Possessing something was the death of love
        for Francis. Also, Francis reasoned, what could you do to a man who owns nothing? You can\'t starve a fasting
        man, you can\'t steal from someone who has no money, you can\'t ruin someone who hates prestige. They were truly
        free.
        \n\n
        Francis was a man of action. His simplicity of life extended to ideas and deeds. If there was a simple way, no
        matter how impossible it seemed, Francis would take it. So when Francis wanted approval for his brotherhood, he
        went straight to Rome to see Pope Innocent III. You can imagine what the pope thought when this beggar
        approached him! As a matter of fact he threw Francis out. But when he had a dream that this tiny man in rags
        held up the tilting Lateran basilica, he quickly called Francis back and gave him permission to preach.
        \n\n
        Francis acted quickly because he acted from the heart; he didn\'t have time to put on a role. Once he was so
        sick and exhausted, his companions borrowed a mule for him to ride. When the man who owned the mule recognized
        Francis he said, \"Try to be as virtuous as everyone thinks you are because many have a lot of confidence in
        you.\" Francis dropped off the mule and knelt before the man to thank him for his advice.
        \n\n
        Another example of his directness came when he decided to go to Syria to convert the Moslems while the Fifth
        Crusade was being fought. In the middle of a battle, Francis decided to do the simplest thing and go straight to
        the sultan to make peace. When he and his companion were captured, the real miracle was that they weren\'t
        killed. Instead Francis was taken to the sultan who was charmed by Francis and his preaching. He told Francis,
        \"I would convert to your religion which is a beautiful one — but both of us would be murdered.\"
        \n\n
        Francis did find persecution and martyrdom of a kind — not among the Moslems, but among his own brothers. When
        he returned to Italy, he came back to a brotherhood that had grown to 5000 in ten years. Pressure came from
        outside to control this great movement, to make them conform to the standards of others. His dream of radical
        poverty was too harsh, people said. Francis responded, \"Lord, didn\'t I tell you they wouldn\'t trust you?\"
        \n\n
        He finally gave up authority in his order — but he probably wasn\'t too upset about it. Now he was just another
        brother, like he\'d always wanted.
        \n\n
        Francis\' final years were filled with suffering as well as humiliation. Praying to share in Christ\'s passion
        he had a vision received the stigmata, the marks of the nails and the lance wound that Christ suffered, in his
        own body.
        \n\n
        Years of poverty and wandering had made Francis ill. When he began to go blind, the pope ordered that his eyes
        be operated on. This meant cauterizing his face with a hot iron. Francis spoke to \"Brother Fire\": \"Brother
        Fire, the Most High has made you strong and beautiful and useful. Be courteous to me now in this hour, for I
        have always loved you, and temper your heat so that I can endure it.\" And Francis reported that Brother Fire
        had been so kind that he felt nothing at all.
        \n\n
        How did Francis respond to blindness and suffering? That was when he wrote his beautiful Canticle of the Sun
        that expresses his brotherhood with creation in praising God.
        \n\n
        Francis never recovered from this illness. He died on October 4, 1226 at the age of 45. Francis is considered
        the founder of all Franciscan orders and the patron saint of ecologists and merchants.


    </string>
    <string name="brief_angel">
        Heaven is the place of immortality, eternal glory and happiness. The angels praise and glorify Him, who is
        worthy of eternal praise. The angels in heaven always see the face of the Heavenly Father.
        \n\n
        In the Nicene creed, it is said, \"I believe in God the Creator of all things, visible and invisible\". Angels
        are the invisible ones, they have no body, they are pure spirits. The presence of angels is everywhere. They are
        immortal have more intelligence and power than men.
        \n\n
        The angels are countless as David says, \"the chariots of God are thousands and millions of millions\". In
        Revelations, St John saw the Lamb of God on the throne and was attended by thousands of Angels.
        \n\n
        The Angels are free creatures, they are called to know the truth by their instinctive power. The Angels do not
        have age or gender, there is no marriage in Heaven. The Angels are pure spirits and they have a free world. St
        Agustine says, \"Angel is the name of their work, Spirit is the name of their nature.\"
        \n\n
        The existence of Angels was confirmed by the 4th Lateran Counsil in 1215. God in the beginning of time created
        supernatural beings and bodily beings together, i.e. beings like angels and those with body. Man was created
        with both natures. That is, He created man with both body and Spirit. In other words, God created both these
        realities right in the beginning-Spiritual reality and bodily reality-the material world and the world of
        angels. He did this to create man, who is a combination of both Spirit and Matter. The faith of the Church
        accepts along with their existence, some particular characteristics in the nature of Angels their total super
        naturalism without any materiality and their immortality. The angels have no body.
        \n\n
        They are closer to God than earthly creatures. They form a close circle around the creator. The Holy scriptures
        give a proof that they are close to God as it regards them as \"Army of God\", \"His heavens\".
    </string>
    <string name="memorare">
        Remember, O most gracious Virgin Mary, that never was it known that anyone who fled to thy protection, implored
        thy help, or sought thine intercession was left unaided.
        \n\n
        Inspired by this confidence, I fly unto thee, O Virgin of virgins, my mother; to thee do I come, before thee I
        stand, sinful and sorrowful. O Mother of the Word Incarnate, despise not my petitions, but in thy mercy
        hear and
        answer me.
        \n\n
        Amen.\n\n\n

    </string>
    <string name="memorare_mar">
        हे मायाळू कुमारी मरिये, जो कोणी आपल्या संरक्षणासाठी तुझ्याकडे धावत आला, तुझे साहाय्य मागितले व तुझ्या मध्यस्थीची
        याचना केली, त्याच्याकडे तू पाठ फिरवलीस असे कोणी कधी ऐकले नाही, हे तू ध्यानात घे. \n\nहे परमश्रेष्ठ कुमारी आणि
        माता,
        तुझ्या चांगुलपणावर विसंबून मी पश्चात्तापी, तुझ्याकडे धाव घेतो, तुझ्याजवळ येतो आणि तुझ्यापुढे उभा राहतो, हे
        देवपुत्राचे माते, माझी विनंती नाकारू नकोस तर कृपा करून ती ऐक आणि मान्य कर.\n\nआमेन
    </string>
    <string name="the_mysteries_of_the_rosary">The Mysteries of the Rosary</string>
    <!--    <string name="cred_mar">प्रेषितांचा विश्वासांगिकार\n\n स्वर्ग आणि पृथ्वी यांचा उत्पन्नकर्ता । सर्व समर्थ परमेश्वर-->
    <!--        पिता । यावर माझा विश्वास आहे । त्याचा एकुलता एक पुत्र । आमचा प्रभू येशू ख्रिस्त । यावरहीमाझा विश्वास आहे । तो-->
    <!--        पवित्र आत्म्याच्या योगाने गर्भी संभवला कुमारी मरियेपासून जन्मला। पोन्ती पिलाताच्या अमलाखाली । त्याने दुःख भोगले।-->
    <!--        त्याला क्रुसावर खिळले। तो मरण पावला । त्याला पुरले । तो अधोलोकांत उतरला । तिसऱ्या दिवशी मेलेल्यांतून उठला ।-->
    <!--        स्वर्गात चढला आणि सर्वसमर्थ देवपित्याच्या उजवीकडे बसला आहे । तेथून तो जिवंत आणि मेलेले । यांचा न्याय करावयास ।-->
    <!--        पुन्हा येईल । पवित्र आत्मा । पवित्र कॅथोलिक ख्रिस्तसभा । संतांचा परस्पर संबंध । पापांची क्षमा देहाचे पुनरूत्थान-->
    <!--        । आणि अनंतकाळचे जीवन । यावर माझा विश्वास आहे । \n\nआमेन.-->
    <!--    </string>-->
    <!--    <string name="creed_mar">प्रेषितांचा विश्वासांगिकार \n\n स्वर्ग आणि पृथ्वी यांचा उत्पन्नकर्ता । सर्व-->
    <!--        समर्थ-->
    <!--        परमेश्वर-->
    <!--        पिता । यावर माझा विश्वास आहे । त्याचा एकुलता एक पुत्र । आमचा प्रभू येशू ख्रिस्त । यावरहीमाझा विश्वास आहे । तो-->
    <!--        पवित्र-->
    <!--        आत्म्याच्या योगाने गर्भी संभवला कुमारी मरियेपासून जन्मला। पोन्ती पिलाताच्या अमलाखाली । त्याने दुःख भोगले। त्याला-->
    <!--        क्रुसावर खिळले। तो मरण पावला । त्याला पुरले । तो अधोलोकांत उतरला । तिसऱ्या दिवशी मेलेल्यांतून उठला । स्वर्गात-->
    <!--        चढला आणि सर्वसमर्थ देवपित्याच्या उजवीकडे बसला आहे । तेथून तो जिवंत आणि मेलेले । यांचा न्याय करावयास । पुन्हा-->
    <!--        येईल । पवित्र आत्मा । पवित्र कॅथोलिक ख्रिस्तसभा । संतांचा परस्पर संबंध । पापांची क्षमा देहाचे पुनरूत्थान । आणि-->
    <!--        अनंतकाळचे जीवन । यावर माझा विश्वास आहे । \n\n आमेन.-->
    <!--    </string>-->

    <string name="Mystery_of_rosary">
        <font color="#D2042D">Joyful Mystery of the Rosary \n(Monday and Saturday)</font>
        \n\n\n1.The Annunciation of the Lord to Mary
        \n\n2.The Visitation of Mary to Elizabeth
        \n\n3.The Nativity of our Lord Jesus Christ
        \n\n4.The Presentation of our Lord
        \n\n5.Finding Jesus in the Temple
        <font color="#D2042D">\n\n\nSorrowful Mystery of the Rosary \n(Tuesday and Friday)</font>
        \n\n1.The Agony of Jesus in the Garden
        \n\n2.The Scourging at the Pillar
        \n\n3.Jesus is Crowned with Thorns
        \n\n4.Jesus Carried the Cross
        \n\n5.The Crucifixion of our Lord
        <font color="#D2042D">\n\n\nGlorious Mystery of the Rosary \n(Wednesday and Sunday)</font>
        \n\n1.The Resurrection of Jesus Christ
        \n\n2.The Ascension of Jesus to Heaven
        \n\n3.The Descent of the Holy Spirit
        \n\n4.The Assumption of Mary into Heaven
        \n\n5.Mary is Crowned as Queen of Heaven and Earth
        <font color="#D2042D">\n\n\nLuminous Mystery of the Rosary \n(Thursday)</font>
        \n\n1.The Baptism in the Jordan
        \n\n2.The Wedding at Cana
        \n\n3.The Proclamation of the Kingdom
        \n\n4.The Transfiguration
        \n\n5.The Institution of the Eucharist
    </string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="creed_mar">प्रेषितांचा विश्वासांगिकार\n\n स्वर्ग आणि पृथ्वी यांचा उत्पन्नकर्ता । सर्व समर्थ परमेश्वर
        पिता । यावर माझा विश्वास आहे । त्याचा एकुलता एक पुत्र । आमचा प्रभू येशू ख्रिस्त । यावरहीमाझा विश्वास आहे । तो
        पवित्र आत्म्याच्या योगाने गर्भी संभवला कुमारी मरियेपासून जन्मला। पोन्ती पिलाताच्या अमलाखाली । त्याने दुःख भोगले।
        त्याला क्रुसावर खिळले। तो मरण पावला । त्याला पुरले । तो अधोलोकांत उतरला । तिसऱ्या दिवशी मेलेल्यांतून उठला ।
        स्वर्गात चढला आणि सर्वसमर्थ देवपित्याच्या उजवीकडे बसला आहे । तेथून तो जिवंत आणि मेलेले । यांचा न्याय करावयास ।
        पुन्हा येईल । पवित्र आत्मा । पवित्र कॅथोलिक ख्रिस्तसभा । संतांचा परस्पर संबंध । पापांची क्षमा देहाचे पुनरूत्थान
        । आणि अनंतकाळचे जीवन । यावर माझा विश्वास आहे । \n\nआमेन.
    </string>
    <string name="litany"> Lord, have mercy. <font color="#FFA500">Lord, have mercy.</font>\n
        Christ, have mercy. <font color="#FFA500">Christ, have mercy</font>\n
        Lord, have mercy. <font color="#FFA500">Lord, have mercy</font>\n
        Christ, hear us. <font color="#FFA500">Christ, hear us</font>\n
        Christ, graciously hear us. <font color="#FFA500">Christ, graciously hear us</font>\n\n


        God, the Father of heaven,  <font color="#FFA500">have mercy on us.</font>\n
        God the Son, Redeemer of the world,  <font color="#FFA500">have mercy on us.</font>\n
        God the Holy Spirit,   <font color="#FFA500">have mercy on us.</font>\n
        Holy Trinity, one God,  <font color="#FFA500">have mercy on us.</font>\n\n


        Holy Mary,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Holy Mother of God,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Holy Virgin of virgins,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother of Christ,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother of the Church,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother of divine grace,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother most pure,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother most chaste,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother inviolate,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother undefiled,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother most amiable,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother most admirable,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother of good counsel,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother of our Creator,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mother of our Savior,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Virgin most prudent,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Virgin most venerable,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Virgin most renowned,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Virgin most powerful,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Virgin most merciful,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Virgin most faithful,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Mirror of justice,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Seat of wisdom,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Cause of our joy,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Spiritual vessel,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Vessel of honor,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Singular vessel of devotion, <font color="#FFA500">pray for  us.</font>\n
        Mystical rose,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Tower of David,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Tower of ivory,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        House of gold,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Ark of the covenant,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Gate of heaven,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Morning star,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n

        Health of the sick,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Refuge of sinners,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Comforter of the afflicted,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Help of Christians,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Angels,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Patriarchs,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Prophets,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Apostles,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Martyrs,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Confessors,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of Virgins,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of all Saints,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen conceived without original sin,   <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen assumed into heaven, <font color="#FFA500">pray for  us.</font>\n
        Queen of the most holy Rosary, <font color ="#FFA500">pray  for us.</font>\n
        Queen of families,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n
        Queen of peace,  <font color="#FFA500">pray for us.</font>\n\n\n


        Lamb of God, You take away sins of  the world, <font color="#FFA500">spare us, O Lord.</font>\n\n
        Lamb of God, You take away the sins of the world, <font color="#FFA500">graciously hear us, O Lord.</font>\n\n
        Lamb of God, You take away the sins of the world, <font color ="#FFA500">have mercy on us.</font>
        \n\n\n

        Pray for us, O holy Mother of God.\n
        <font color="#FFA500">That we may be made worthy of the promises of Christ.</font>\n
        \nLet us pray.\nGrant, we beseech You, O Lord God, that we, Your servants may enjoy perpetual health
        of mind and body, and by the glorious intercession of the Blessed Mary, ever Virgin,
        may be delivered from present sorrow and obtain eternal joy.
        Through Christ our Lord. \n\nAmen.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_litany">LitanyActivity</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <string name="mystery_mar"><font color="#D2042D">आनंदाची रहस्ये (सोमवारी व शनिवारी)</font>\n\n

        १. देवदुताने मरियेला संदेश दिला \n\n

        २. मरियेने एलिझाबेथची भेट घेतली.\n\n

        ३. बाळ येशू गाईच्या गोठ्यात जन्मला\n\n

        ४. मरियेने येशूबाळाला मंदिरात भेटवले\n\n

        ५. येशू मंदिरात सापडला.\n\n\n

        <font color="#D2042D">दुःखाची रहस्ये (मंगळवारी व शुक्रवारी)</font> \n\n

        १. गेथसेमनी बागेत येशूला रक्ताचा घाम आला.\n\n

        २. येशूच्या अंगावर फटके मारले.\n\n

        ३. येशूच्या मस्तकावर काट्यांचा मुकुट घातला.\n\n

        ४. येशूने भारी क्रूस वाहिला\n\n

        ५. येशूला क्रुसावर खिळले.\n\n\n

        <font color="#D2042D">प्रकाशाची रहस्ये (गुरूवारी)</font> \n\n

        १. प्रभू येशूचा यार्देन नदीत बाप्तिस्मा झाला.\n\n

        २. काना येथे प्रभू येशूने पाण्याचे द्राक्षारसात रूपांतर केले.\n\n

        ३. प्रभू येशूने स्वर्गराज्याची घोषणा करून पश्चात्तापासाठी आवाहन केले.\n\n

        ४. प्रभू येशूचे रूपांतर झाले.\n\n

        ५. पास्का रहस्याची आठवण म्हणून प्रभू येशूने पवित्र मिस्साबलीची स्थापना केली.\n\n\n

        <font color="#D2042D">गौरवाची रहस्ये (रविवारी व बुधवारी)</font>\n\n

        १. येशू मेलेल्यातून तिसऱ्या दिवशी पुन्हा उठला.\n\n

        २. येशू चाळीस दिवसानंतर स्वर्गात चढला.\n\n

        ३. पवित्र आत्मा प्रेषितांवर उतरला.\n\n

        ४. पवित्र मरिया सदेह स्वर्गात घेतली गेली. \n\n

        ५. पवित्र मरिया स्वर्ग आणि पृथ्वीची राणी झाली

    </string>
    <string name="litany_mar">
        मरियेची विनंतीमाला

        हे ईश्वरा, आम्हावर दया कर,   <font color="#FFA500">हे ईश्वरा,आम्हावर दया कर,</font>\n

        हे ख्रिस्ता, आम्हावर दया कर,   <font color="#FFA500">हे ख्रिस्ता,आम्हावर दया कर,</font>\n

        हे ईश्वरा, आम्हावर दया कर,  <font color="#FFA500">हे ईश्वरा, आम्हावर दया कर,</font>\n

        हे ख्रिस्ता, आमचे ऐक, <font color="#FFA500">हे ख्रिस्ता, आमचे ऐक,</font>\n

        हे ख्रिस्ता, आमचे ऐकून घे, <font color="#FFA500">हे ख्रिस्ता, आमचे ऐकून घे,</font>\n\n

        हे देवा, स्वर्गातील बापा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हावर दया कर</font>\n

        हे देवपुत्रा, जगत्तारका,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हावर दया कर</font>\n


        हे देवा, पवित्र आत्म्या,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हावर दया कर</font>\n


        हे पवित्र त्रैक्या, एकच देवा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हावर दया कर</font>\n\n

        हे पवित्र मरिये,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n


        हे पवित्र देवमाते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        पवित्र कुमारींचे कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        ख्रिस्ताचे माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        ईश्वरकृपेचे माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        आशेचे माने,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        अतिशुद्ध माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n


        अतिविरक्त माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        निर्दोष माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        निष्कलंक माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        प्रियकर माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        आश्चर्यकारक माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        चांगल्या मसलतीचे माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        उत्पन्नकर्त्याचे माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        तारणाऱ्याचे माते,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        अतिसमंजस कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        आदरणीय कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        स्तुतियोग्य कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        शक्तिमान कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        दयाळू कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        विश्वासू कुमारी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        नीतीच्या आरशा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        ज्ञानाच्या आसना,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        आमच्या आनंदाच्या कारणा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        परमार्थ बुद्धीच्या पात्रा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        सन्मानाच्या पात्रा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        सुभक्तीच्या उत्कृष्ट पात्रा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        रहस्यमय गुलाबा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        दाविदाच्या बुरूजा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        हस्तिदंती बुरूजा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        सोन्याच्या घरा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        कराराच्या कोशा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        स्वर्गाच्या दरवाजा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        सकाळच्या नक्षत्रा,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n
        रोग्यांच्या आरोग्या,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        विस्थापित झालेल्यांचे सांत्वना,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        पाप्यांच्या आश्रया,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n


        दुःखितांच्या सांत्वना,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        ख्रिस्तीजनांच्या सहाय्या,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        देवदूतांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        आदिपितरांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        भविष्यवाद्यांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        प्रेषितांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        रक्तसाक्ष्यांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        वर्तनसाक्ष्यांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        कुमारींचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        सर्व पवित्रांचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        मूळ पापावाचून संभवलेले राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        स्वर्गात सदेह नेलेले राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        पवित्र मालेचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        कुटुंबाचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n

        शांततेचे राणी,  <font color="#FFA500">आम्हासाठी विनंती कर</font>\n \n

        जगाची पापे दूर करणाऱ्या परमेश्वराच्या कोकरा <font color="#FFA500">आम्हाला माफ कर, हे प्रभो.</font>\n
        जगाची पापे दूर करणाऱ्या परमेश्वराच्या कोकरा <font color="#FFA500">आमचे ऐकून घे. हे प्रभो</font>\n
        जगाची पापे दूर करणाऱ्या परमेश्वराच्या कोकरा <font color="#FFA500">आम्हावर दया कर</font>\n\nआपण प्रार्थना करू या हे, \nपरमेश्वरा आम्हा तुझ्या सेवकांना आत्म्याचे व शरीराचे स्वास्थ्य नित्य लाभावे आणि नित्य कुमारी धन्य मरिया हिच्या प्रतापी याचनेने हल्लीच्या दुःखातून आम्ही मुक्त व्हावे व सर्वकाळचा आनंद उपभोगावा असे आम्हाला कृपादान दे. ही प्रार्थना आम्ही आमच्या प्रभुखिस्ताद्वारे करतो. \n\nआमेन

    </string>

</resources>
